Since the beginning of time...
Since the first little
girl ever existed
There have been
Dolls
But dolls were always and forever
Baby dolls
The girls who played with them
could only every play at being mother
Which can be fun...
At least for a while anyway
Ask your mother
This continued until
Yes, Barbie changed everything
Then she changed it all again
All of these women are Barbie
and Barbie is all of these women
She might have started out
as just a lady in a bathing suit,
but she became so much more
She has her own money, her own house,
her own car, her own career
Because Barbie can be
anything, women can be anything
And this has been reflected back
onto the little girls of
today in the real world
Girls can grow into women
who can achieve everything
and anything they set their mind to
Thanks to Barbie
all problems of feminism and equal rights
have been solved
At least that's what the Barbies think
After all, they're living in Barbie Land
Who am I to burst their bubble?
And here is one of those Barbies now
Living her best day every day
When you're playing with Barbies
Nobody bothers to walk them
down the stairs and out the door etc.
You just pick them up and put
them where you want them to go
You use your imagination.
- Hi, Skipper!
- Hi, Barbie!
Hi, Midge!
Midge was Barbie's
pregnant friend.
Well let's not show Midge actually
She was discontinued by Mattel
because a pregnant
doll is just too weird.
Anyway, Barbie has
another big day ahead of her.
Hi, Barbie!
- Hi, Barbie!
- Morning, Barbie!
Hi!
- Have another great day!
- Good morning Barbie!
Hi!
Hey, ladies!
Everybody, turn to
the Barbie next to you.
Tell her how much you
love her, compliment her.
Reporter Barbie, you can
ask me any question you want.
How come you're so amazing?
No comment.
No seriously, no comment.
I love you guys.
The Nobel Prize for Journalism
goes to Barbie!
I work very hard so
I deserve it.
And the Nobel Prize for
Literature goes to Barbie.
- You are the voice of a generation.
- I know.
In our assessment,
money is not speech and
corporations have no free
speech rights to begin with
So any claim on their part
to be exercising their right
is just their attempt to turn
our democracy into a plutocracy
This makes me emotional
and I'm expressing it
I have no difficulty holding both
logic and feeling at the same time
And it does not diminish my powers
It expands them
Hi Barbie!
What can't Barbie do?
- Hi, Barbie!
Yay space!
Gosh
Barbie has a great
day every day
But Ken only has a great
day if Barbie looks at him.
- Hi, Barbie!
- Hi, Ken!
Hi, Barbie!
Hi, Ken!
Hi, Ken.
- Hi, Ken!
- I us both got ice creams
- Cool
- Hi, Barbie!
Hi, Barbie!
- Hi, Ken!
- Hi, Barbie!
Hi, Barbie!
- Hi, Barbies!
- Bye, Barbies!
Hi, Barbie!
Oh hi, Alan!
There are no multiples
of Alan, he's just Alan
Yeah I'm ... uh ....
confused about that
Hey Barbie, check me out
Ken!
- Ken?
- Oh hey, Barbie
Hi
How much of that did you see?
We saw the whole thing
Let's get you up
on your feet Ken
- You're just so strong
- Use your legs
- Are you ok?
- Yep
Looks like this beach was a
little too much beach for you, Ken
If I wasn't severly injured I would
beach you off right now, Ken
I'll beach off with
you any day, Ken
Hold my ice cream, Ken
Alright Ken, you're on
Let's beach off
Anyone who wants to beach
him off has to beach me off first
I will beach both of
you off at the same time
But you don't even know how
to beach yourself off, how are
- you going to beach both of
- Okay...
us off that doesn't make sense
- Kens?
- Why are you getting emotional?
- You're going to beach both of us off?
- No one's going to beach anyone off
Okay?
Let's go
Okay, okay
- Barbie, hold my hand
- You're okay
Stay with me, Barbie
Great, not even broken.
You'll be fine
Shredding waves is much more
dangerous than people realize
You're very brave, Ken
- Thank you, Barbie
- Yeah
You know surfer is not even my job
- I know
- And it is not lifeguard
Which is a common misconception
Very common
Yeah cus actually my job
- It's just beach
- Right
- And what a good job you do at beach
- You should heal up in no time
Actually, in the time that it
took for me to say that sentence
you healed
- Fantastic
- Nice!
- Hey Barbie
- Yeah?
- Can I come to your house tonight?
- Sure!
I don't have anything big
planned, just a giant blow out party
with all the Barbies and planned
choreography and a bespoke song
You should stop by
- So, cool?
- Yeah. Okay
- Bye!
- Ok, bye. Goodbye
- Hi, Barbie
- Hi, Ken
- Looking good, Barbie!
- Thanks, Ken!
- Oh hi, Ken!
- Hi
- Hi, Barbie!
Barbie!
What's up, Ken?
Hey Barbie, check me out
Bet you can't do
a flip like that, Ken
What?
- This is a real rager, Barbie.
- Thanks, Barbie!
Gosh
This night is just perfect!
It's perfectly perfect
And you look so beautiful, Barbie
- Thanks, Barbie. I feel so beautiful
- So do I
- This is the best day ever
- It is the best day ever
And so was yesterday
and so is tomorrow
and so was the day after
tomorrow and even Wednesdays
every day from
now until forever!
Do you guys ever
think about dying?
I don't know why I just...
I'm just dying to dance!
You can go now
- I thought I might stay over tonight
- Why?
- Because we're girlfriend boyfriend
- To do what?
I'm actually not sure
Oh, but, I don't want you here
- Is it Ken?
- Ken's just a really good friend
And this is my Dream House,
it's Barbie's Dream House
It's not Ken's Dream House, right?
- Right as always
- And it's girl's night
Come on, Barbie!  Slumber Party!
- Hurry up, the President's here
- I am! You're welcome
- Every night is girl's night?
- Mmhm. Every night.  Forever.
- Every night
- Forever and ever
- Good night
I love you too
Girl's night! Girls night! Girls night!
I can't. I gotta go
Good night, Barbies! I'm definitely
not thinking about death anymore
Hi, Barbie!
Ooh, girl you okay?
I'm fine.  A-okay!
- You got it, Barbie!
- Let's go, Barbie!
Great cheer, Kens
Come on, Barbie, let's
run towards the water
Okay
My feet!
Oh no
- Hey, Barbie!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, Barbie, I just fell
- Fell?
I'm so embarrassed
Barbie doesn't get embarrassed
I know.  Barbie, I... I don't
even have context for this
but my feet, my heels
are on the ground
- I'm no longer on tiptoes
- That's okay. Let me see
Flatfeet!
Stop it, Ken
I'm sorry, I'm sorry
I know I'm stereotypical
Barbie and therefore don't form
conjectures concerning the
causality of adjacent unfolding events
but some things are
happening that might be related
Bad breath this morning, a cold shower,
burnt waffle, and falling off my roof
- You're malfunctioning
- What?  No!  I'm just, I'm...
- Am I?
- I've never seen this kind of malfunction before
It's usually just hair related
You know, you're going to
have to visit Weird Barbie
- I have never had to visit Weird Barbie
- That's because you've never malfunctioned
I heard she that she used to
be the most beautiful Barbie of all
but then somebody played with
her too hard in The Real World
And now she's fated to an eternity
of making other Barbies perfect
while falling more and
more into disrepair herself
That and we all call her Weird Barbie
both behind her back and also to her face
She's so weird
Why is she always in the splits?
I would never wear heels if
my feet were shaped this way
Hello
Woof
Bark
Hey
What's cookin' good lookin'?
- Hi
- Welcome
Welcome to my Weird House
- Hi, how are ya?
- Nice to met you
Sorry for the dog crap.
What can I do ya for?
I just had to come
see you about my feet
They're um...
Flat!
Yeah
- Never seen that before
- Really?
Okay, well can you...
you know, fix them?
- You're stereotypical Barbie, right?
- Mmhmm
That Ken of yours
- He is one nice lookin' little protein pot
- I guess
I'd like to see what kind of nude
blob he's packing under those jeans
- Anyway, what preceeded this?
- Oh, nothing
A really fun game of volleyball
- That's it?
- Thoughts of death...
What is...
Maybe some
- Thoughts of death?
- Thoughts of death?!
- Is that a problem?
- Ohhh
- What?
- I've heard this
Of course I didn't
think it was possible
But it's real
Oh, you've done it.
You've opened a portal
- I didn't open a portal
- Someone did
And now there is a rift
in the continuum that is the membrane
between Barbie Land and the Real World
and if you want to be
stereotypical Barbie perfect again
then baby girl,
you've gotta go fix it
Or you're going to keep going funny.
Look at your upper thigh
- What is that?
- That's cellulite
- That's going to spread everywhere
- What?
And then you're going to start
getting sad and mushy and complicated
No!
What do I have to do?
You have to go to the Real World
And you will find the
girl who's playing with you
- Playing with me?
- We're all getting played with, babe
But usually there's some
kind of separation.  Thanks
There's the girl and the doll
and never the twains shall cross
- The twain is crossing?
- Yes
And the girl who's playing with you
she must be sad and her thoughts
and feelings and humanness
are interferring with your dollness
Why would she be sad?
We fixed everything so that all women in
the real world can be happy and powerful
I don't know, but if you ask me
you had something to do with this too
- Me?
- It takes two rift a portal
I can't have. I've only every wanted for
everything to stay exactly as it is
Well be that as it may, the two of you
are becoming inextricably intertwined
And you gotta help
her to help yourself
So should...
So what'll it be then?
You can go back to your regular life
and forget any of this ever happened
Or you can know the
truth about the universe
The choice is now yours
The first one. The high heel
No.
We'll do a redo
You're supposed
to want to know
I don't
Babe? Listen? You have to
want to know, okay?  Do it again
I'm not Adventure Barbie,
I'm Stereotypical Barbie
I'm like the Barbie you think of when
someone says, "Think of a Barbie"
That's me
I'm bummed. You're a bummer
- That's a bummer
- Okay
- I'm ready to forget now
- No, you're do-ing-this-one
I just gave you choice so you
could feel some sense of control
So there is no option 1?
No, you have to
fix the rift yourself
Don't blame me, blame
Mattel. They make the rules
- I don't want too!
- Fine, get cellulite. I don't care
No, no no no, no. Okay
Send me through the portal
Okay, there's actually no portal.
It's a figure of speech
It's actually a sports
car to a speedboat...
to a rocketship to a tandem bike...
to a camper van
finally to a snowmobile
Which will take you most of the
way to the state of Los Angeles
where you will don
neon and rollerblades
and then through the
country of California
Weird, I know. Best if you
don't think about it too much
And then when I get
there, how do I find this girl?
You will know
Okay
- And how do I get back?
- The same way you came, but in reverse
Like I should move forward,
but through the order backward...
- Don't overthink it
- Oh, okay
For you see...
If you don't find
her and fix things,
what's ugly will become uglier,
and what's weird will become weirder
And then you'll look like me
Sorry.
I understand.
I set myself up for that.
Anyway, I believe in you
- Thank you
- Go. Be careful
I love you
- Bye
Bon voyage to reality
and good luck
restoring the membrane
that separates our world from theirs
so you don't get cellulite!
- I guess she's going without you
- You're so lost, Ken
She literally asked me
- And I was like, "I prefer to stay here"
- Why?
- Are you scared?
- No.
I bet you're scared and I bet
she doesn't even want you to go
Well you bet both those things incorrectly,
and I bet in the opposite direction
- Yeah?
- Yeah
Which way is that?
You don't even know
I just don't want to leave.
I'm trying to find reasons not to leave
- Please stay
- I'm going to miss you guys so much
I just wish someone
could come with me
But you can't. I
should do this alone.
What bird am I thinking of?
-Parrot
-Dolphin.  I mean, no, a bird
Pelican
Man
We'll miss you, Barbie
I'll be back in no
time with perfect feet
and we'll forget that
this ever happened
And you'll get to see all the good
work we've done to fix the world
You'll be such a hero to them
All those grateful powerful women
who owe their wonderful lives to Barbie
I'll bet every woman will say thank
you and give you a really big hug
Yes, you're right!
Here I go!
Bye!
- Bye, Barbie.
- Bye!
Bye, Barbie.
Good luck in reality
Watch out for cellulite!
I went to the doctor,
I went to the mountains
I looked to the children,
I drank from the fountains
There's more than one
answer to these questions
Pointing me in a crooked line
And the less I seek my
source for some definitive
Closer I am to fine
- Closer I am to fi...
- What are you doing here?
- I'm coming with ya
- No, please get out
- I can't
I made a double bet with Ken, and...
you can't make me look
uncool in front of Ken
- Ken's not cool!
- He is to me
You're just going
to slow me down
What if there's beach?
You'll need someone
who's a professional in that
Did you bring your rollerblades?
I literally go nowhere without them
Please?
Okay
Let's do this
- Can I sit in the front?
- No
REAL WORLD this way
And so Barbie and Ken
set off on their adventure
to the Real World
Hi
Barbie!
This is the Real World!
Barbie, I told you
there would be beach
Yeah
- What's going on?
- Give us a smile, blondie
- Why are these men looking at me?
- Yeah, they're also staring at me
- Ooh, love that
- Wow
I feel kind of ill at ease, like
I don't know the word for it, but I'm...
conscious, but it's...
myself that I'm conscious of
I'm not getting any of that. I feel
what can only be described as "admire"
But not ogle
And there's no
undertone of violence
Mine very much has
an undertone of violence
Oh look, a construction site
We need that good
feminine energy
Ladies, yoohoo!
Oh, you got fries
with that shake?
If I said you had a hot body
would you hold it against me?
- You don't have a mirror in your pocket?
- Baby, you are an angel!
- I can see myself in your shorts
I don't know exactly what you
meant with all of those little quips
But I'm picking up on some sort of
entendre which appears to be double
and I would just like to inform
you: I do not have a vagina
And he does not have a penis
- We don't have genitals
- That's okay
I have all... all the genitals
Geez, you would think a
construction site at lunchtime
would be the perfect place
for a little woman power
This one was so...
male
Everything's almost like...
reversed here
Oh look!
- The Supreme Court
- They're so smart
- I love me a leotard
- I love the elbow pads
I... I think we should get
some different clothes
We look great
- I love fringe
- I love denim
Hey, man!
You guys gotta pay for that stuff
- She looks even better in more clothes
- Because you can imagine more
Do you know what?  Keep 'em.
Weird Barbie said I would know
how to find this girl, but I have no idea
What would a Smart Barbie do?
I just need to clear
my mind so I can think
Who is playing with me?
I hate it when people
think. It gets so boring
The faster I figure it out,
the faster we get to go home
- What am I supposed to do?
- Ken! Go for a walk or something
By myself?
- Yes
- Really? Where?
Anywhere!
- Can I go that way?
- Yes. Okay
- Don't go far.
- Okay!
Excuse me, sir
Thanks, man
What's up, man?
- We gotta man up on this one
- Great workout, man
Men, men, men!
- You're the man!
- No, you're the man
Men, men, men!
Based on earnings, we
exceeded expectations
So I'm not worried about it
Not now, Margaret.
Let's shake on this
We're officially important
Yes!
That felt...
achy...
but good
You're so beautiful
I know it
Barbie!
Yes!
- I've got it!
- What do you got?
- You go first
- We'll go at the same time
- Okay
- She's at school!
- Men rule the world!
- What was that?
- The kid's at the school?
But what did you say?
- Nothing
- Okay
- Well, let's go to the school!
- Okay!
Now come on
MATTEL HEADQUARTERS
LOS ANGELES, CALIFORNIA
- Hello
- This is Dan with the FBI
This is Aaron at Mattel...
I don't give a flying
squirrel who you are, Aaron
- What are you? Like an intern?
- No...
- Two of your dolls have gotten loose
- Impossible.  How do you know...
Don't sass me, Aaron. Couple of
blondes, answering to Barbie nd Ken
Rollerblading in Santa Monica
We're going to need
Mattel's help landing the eagle
-Don't crap the bed, Aaron
- I won't
This is bad.  This is really bad
- What?
- Th...th... this happened before
What? When?
I heard about 10 years ago, a
woman named, Skipper
turned up at some family's home in
Key West, asked to babysit the kids
She then tried to take
their toddler surfing
- Jeez
- I know
They where able to straighten it
out, keep it under wraps, but this is...
serious
- I'm going all the way up
- No one goes all the way up
- I have to
- You may never come back
I know
- Hey
- Oh hi, Aaron
- New drawings?
- Yeah
I just started drawing
these weird designs
- These are different
- It's Irrepressible Thoughts of Death Barbie.
Full Body Cellulite Barbie
Crippling Shame Barbie
Okay, listen, I have to
speak to the top brass
- No
- I must
- No.
- I'm going to
Aron, they're in a big corporate
idea sesh, no one is to be admitted
... we empowering girls. Always!
But what do we really sell?
I'll tell you what. We sell
dreams. And imagination
And sparkle
I get excited, I'm passionate.
And when you think of sparkle,
what do you think of after that?
Female agency
Excuse me
- Who are you?
- Aaron Dinkins, sir
We're in the middle of a major
sit down here, Aaron Dinkins
I think you're going
to want to hear this, sir
Can you just email it? And
you can send it to me E.O.D.
End Of Day
May I put it in a whisper, sir?
Fine, whisper me
No.
Pointed the chair.
You're okay
- You alright?
- He's okay
It's a repeat of Skipper in Key West
And with all due respect...
That was Skipper,
sir. This is...
Barbie.
If this got out that our dolls were
coming to Los Angeles from Barbie Land
As life sized versions of themselves
Roaming the earth
This would be very bad
Barbie in the real world?
That's impossible
We've got a definite situation on our hands
Catastrophic!
- I can't stress that enough!
- What?
- What's your name again?
- Aaron Dinkins, sir
- Aaron Dickinson?
- Dinkins
Yes, Aaron
Is Barbie Land like an alternate
reality or is it like a place where
- Uh, your imagination
-Yes.
- Okay.
- Think of it as town in Sweden.
Aaron Dinkins
Sweden
Right
How much do you weigh?
Doesn't matter
Sounds like a job for the box
No one rests until this
doll is back in a box
Look, Davy Crockett Junior High
School, just like a saw in my vision
A man on a horse
I've started to get all
these weirdo feelings
Like I have fear with
no specific object
- What is that?
- Anxiety
I have it too. They're
just awful at this age
I feel amazing.
That's because kids don't
take it out on their dads
She's gotta be here somewhere.
We need to find her soon
I'm just going to pop into the library
and see if I can find any books on trucks
- Okay, just don't get in trouble
- I won't!
What are you doing?
Oh! Uhh
What's that girl's name?
That's Sasha
Hey, Sasha!
- Don't talk to her!
- Oh
Sasha can talk to you
but you never talk to Sasha
- She'll crush you
- Don't worry
Everyone really likes me
and thinks I'm cool and pretty
- Huh
- Thank you
Hey, ladies. Sasha
What's up?
Who are you?
I'm only your favorite
woman of all time
Barbie!
You really think
you're Barbie?
- Yeah
- She's crazy
Do you think she escaped
from like an insane asylum?
- So you're like Barbie Barbie
- Like a professional bimbo?
No, Barbie's not a bimbo. Barbie is a
doctor and a lawyer and a senator and a...
- ... Nobel prize winner.
- You're a Nobel prize winner?
Oh, no, not me, but...
Barbie is ... yeah
Aren't you guys going to
thank me and give me a big hug?
For being your favorite toy
We haven't played with Barbie's
since we were like five years old
Yeah, I hated dolls with hair
I mean, I played with Barbie,
but it was like the last resort
I loved Barbie
Anyways, even then
it was horrible for us
It was horrible?
Why?
- Come on, Sasha
- Give it to her
Destroy Barbie
Okay, Barbie
Let's do this
You've been making women feel bad
about themselves since you were invented
I think you have that
the wrong way around
You represent everything
wrong with our culture
Sexualized capitalism,
unrealistic physical ideals
No, no, no...
You're describing something stereotypical.
Barbie is...
- So much more than that
- Look at yourself
I am technically
Stereotypical Barbie
You set the feminism
movement back 50 years
You destroy girls'
innate sense of worth
and you are killing the planet with
your glorification of rampant consumerism
No, I'm supposed to help you
and make you happy and powerful
Oh, I am powerful.  And until you showed
up here and declared yourself Barbie
I hadn't thought about
you in years, you fascist
Oh. Um
Okay
It's happening again
I have to... will you excuse me?
It was really
nice talking to you
They never listen
Excuse me, sir, do you have time?
- You respect me
- Sorry, no, do you know what time it is?
No, I do not
- Okay
- Why didn't Barbie tell me about patriarchy?
Which, to my understanding, is
where men in horses run everything?
Sure
- I shall seek my fortune then
- Alright
I'll take a high level, high
paying job with influence, please
Okay, you'll need at least an MBA.
And a lot of our people have PhDs
- Isn't being a man enough?
- Actually right now it's kind of the opposite.
You guys are clearly not
doing patriarchy very well
No, we're uh...
We're doing it well, yeah.
We just, uh, hide it better, you know.
Oh
No, I won't let you do
just one appendectomy
- But I'm a man
- But not a doctor
- Please?
- No
- Can I talk to a doctor?
- You are talking to a doctor
- Can you get me a coffee
- No
- And I need a clicky pen
- And a white coat. And a sharp thing
- No. No
- There he is. Doctor!
- Somebody get security
- I'd like to apply for your job of beach?
- So you wanna be a lifeguard?
Oh, I'm not trained to go over there. I'm
trained to stand confidently right here.
- There's nobody in danger here.
- And even if there were, I'm not trained to save them
- Then I can't hire you
- I can't even beach here!
She thinks I'm a fascist?
I don't control the railways
or the flow of commerce
- There you are
- Oh no...
That went terrible
I need to find somewhere
where I can start patriarchy fresh
- Miss Barbie?
- It's just "Barbie".
We're going to need
you to come with us
Oh
- Who are you?
- We're Mattel
- Mattel?
- Mattel
Thank goodness. I've got
to talk to somebody in charge
Everything is backwards here.
Men look at me like I'm an object
Girls hate me,
everyone thinks I'm crazy
and I keep getting arrested!
- Would you step this way, ma'am?
- I also just learned to cry
First it I got one tear and
then I got a whole bunch
What to do? Do I follow Barbie into
that scary unmarked black truck car?
A truck car I'd like to have, actually
You're right
She's fine.  It's Mattel
- Yeah
- I know
I'll go back to Barbie Land and
I'll tell the Kens what I've learned
Oh! It's going to be beautiful
- Okay.  Let's go that way
- Back to Barbie Land.
- Hi, bunny boo boo
- Don't call me that
Sorry
I'm off early because
of a crisis at work,
but I thought we could
go get some soft serve
Thank god they
arrested that nutjob
That reality challenged
woman. She thinks she's Barbie
- Wait, what did you say?
- She thinks she's Barbie
She's like really convinced
What are you doing? What are you doing?
Mom.  Mom!
Mom, get back in the car!
Are you kidding me?
Mom!
Mattel! Of course it was you
guys that brought me here
Because it definitely
wasn't that Sasha girl
Thanks for the ride. This
has been so much fun
Wow! The mother ship!
Barbie!  So happy to see you!
- Hi!
- Would you like some mineral water?
- Yes! Thank you
I'm used to that
having anything in it
Thank you
So we've been very anxious to
get some quality face time with you
Of course.  So what can I do to repair
the rift in the space time continuum
and get my feet back
and that one cellulite gone
and just generally not
turn into Weird Barbie?
We have been discussing that very topic
If you're agreeable to it, we
would love it if you could just...
get into that giant box
Get into the box and you'll go back to Barbie
Land. And everything will be as it was
You know what? We should probably get Ken first
- Ken
- You know, Ken. Barbie and Ken
- Yes, Ken! Yeah
- The guy, yeah
Back to Barbie Land!
I'm going to be so...
I'm going to be sick
Ken isn't something
we're worried about
Ever
- Okay, I'll just um... I'll get in the box then
- Alright!
Yes!
Oh, but since I came all this way,
could I just meet the woman in charge?
Your CEO?
Oh, that would be me
- Oh, your CFO
- Me
- Your COO?
- Here
- President of the Barbie Division
- Present
I'm a man with no power,
does that make me a woman?
Are any women in charge?
Listen...
I know exactly where
you're going with this and
I have to say I really resent it!
We are a company
literally made of women
We had a woman CEO in the 90s
And there was another one...
at some other time
So that's... that's
two right there
Women are the freaking foundation
of this very long phallic building
We have gender neutral
bathrooms up the wazoo
Every single one of
these men love women
I'm a son of a mother
I'm the mother of a son
I'm... I'm the nephew of a woman aunt
Some of my best friends are Jewish
What I'm trying to say is...
Get in the box, you jezebel
What? I can't
say "jezebel" now?
I haven't been
in a box in ages
You see?  It's easy
Oh, okay
Oh my gosh, I remember this smell
I'm having a real Proustian flashback
Remember Proust Barbie?
That did not sell very well
Do you know what?
Um, before I get in the box
Could I just run to the restroom
and make sure my hair is perfect?
- Fine. Can you be speedy about it?
- Mmhm
- Down this way?
- It's just down the hallway
- Thank you
- On the right
Guess she really had
to go the bathroom
Get that Barbie!
Don't you dare push
that button. Let me do it
I said, get that Barbie!
Where's Barbie?
I'm gaining on you
I'll capture you
Quicker to go over the cube
- It's quicker
- Sure
Get that Barbie!
Barbie!
I will get you!
Don't worry, you're safe here
What is this place?
I always find I think
best at kitchen tables
Tea?
Uh... yes, please
So a woman does work here
Oh sweety, we do
more than work here
What?
- It's because I don't know how to drink tea?
- No
You look different
It's not how I normally look.
I usually look perfect
Oh, I don't know
I think you're just right
Real World isn't
what I thought it was
It never is
And isn't that marvelous?
Who... are you?
Which way did she go?
If you go through that closet
You'll find a stairwell
down to the lobby
Okay
Thank you
Ruth
Ruth.  Thank you, Ruth
You're welcome, Barbie
Oh, we've got her! There she is!
Keycard! Wait, I don't have my keycard!
Get in!
Now!  Get in now!
Come on!
Oh no!
Now we're never
going to get Barbie
Oh, we didn't need it
Barbie!
Let's form a plan here
I would normally have shotgun.
I'll get the first one
Hang on!
God, I hope nobody from school
saw us put a life-sized Barbie in our car
- How did this even happen?
- I don't know
How are you here?
You're like an idea
A great idea
So, I've been a
little lonely lately
- And I found those Barbies we used to play with
- I thought we gave those away
So I started playing with them and making
drawings like we used to do, remember?
- Because I thought it would be joyful
- Was it?
No, it wasn't. I got sad and weird,
and then the drawings got sad and weird
and maybe because I couldn't be
like you, I ended up making you like me
Did any of these drawings by chance
have thoughts of death and cellulite?
Yes!
Irrepressible Thoughts
of Death Barbie!
-Oh my god!
-And cellulite
- I came for you
- You came for me
Those were your memories
Hello? Hello?
Are you two, like, Shining?
No, no, it's nothing like that
Are you Shining
with a real Barbie?
No!
I mean, maybe, like a little... yes
I don't even know where to start
with this wishing your Barbie to life crap
Oh Sasha, listen
I'm just a boring mom with a boring
job and a daughter who hates me
Can you blame me for
wanting to have a little fun?
I gotta lose these chuckleheads
Mom!
I think I owe you
ladies an apology
I thought that Barbie had
made the Real World better
But the Real World is forever
and irrevocably messed up
Well, the Real World is not
perfect, but you inspired me
I love women. I
want to help women
Oh come off it,
everybody hates women
Women hate women and men hate women,
it's the one thing we can all agree on
- Is that true?
- It's complicated. "Hate" is a strong word
Wake up, mom!
I'm wide awake, Sasha!
Mom, where did you learn to drive like this?
- There was this guy...
- Was it Dad?
Yeah, yeah... it
was... it was Dad
Okay, duck!
- You look so pretty
- Don't look at me
Okay, sorry
I can't hold them off
forever. Where can we go?
Wait, I have an idea. Can
you get us to Venice Beach?
Sure can!
I love rollerblades.
Where are we going?
- Barbie Land
- What? Mom!
Are you really going
to let Barbie take you
and your tween daughter
to an imaginary land?
Yes, and you want to know why?
Because I never get to do anything
I didn't even go on that cruise
I won at your school raffle
because I didn't have enough vacation
days and your dad's allergic to sun
Oh
- What about Dad? We can't just leave him
- He'll be fine
Boligrafos. Boligrafos. Boligrafos
- Yeah, yeah, he'll be fine
- Ready for fun?
Yes!
Here we go! Come
on and feel the magic
Where are we?
- How did we get into these clothes?
- How did we get into this vehicle?
When I was a kid I
lost these boots and
my mom wouldn't let me
buy a whole new Barbie
- ...just to replace the boots
- They look so good on you!
Why thank you!
- Hey you
- She was always my favorite Barbie
You're my favorite human
Don't tell him, but
I never got a Ken
That's because Ken is totally
superfluous... I didn't say that
Women hold all major
positions of power
control all the money, basically everything
that men do in your world, women do in ours
I mean, that sounds kind of cool
Sasha, look! Dolphins!
Closer I am to fine, yeah
Closer I am to fi...
What is this song?!
Oh! And we have a
female president and it's
fun, and work, and
friendship and females 24/7
No giant hands come
in and play with you?
No, that's crazy
Excuse me, have you seen
a group of women on wheels?
Actually yeah, there was
blonde, brunette and a
...tween, they
rollerbladed in that direction
Oh no
First step is always rollerblading
- Excuse me, sir?
- They've gone to Barbie Land
- Oh no
- And she's brought humans there with her
This could mean extremely
weird things for our world
Like what?
Nothing any of our collective
imaginations could ever dream of
A podcast hosted
by two wise trees
Or a choir of 2,000
young fathers
Not even close. We've
got to get to Barbie Land
Go, find some blades now!
Just pick a direction and run
I can practically feel my
heels lifting already. Yes!
This is what I was supposed
to do. Bring you back here
- It feels right
- It does
Okay, this is... oh
That's strange
Incoming brewski beer
See that's our
President with the beer
and the cheering squad
is the Supreme Court
This is so much better
than being President
Something's weird today
Hi, Barbie!
Oh, okay!  Hi, Ken!
Have a brewski beer
My big guy is thirsty
Anyway... uh
Wait until you see
my Dream House
Everything I've bought and
own will totally inspire you
And we can change clothes again!
That's the Capitol!
- It's pink?
- Pink!
And that's...
These are the Dream
Houses. This is where I live
You can see through the houses
So does each Barbie
like have their own house?
Mmhmm
That's cool. Where
do the Kens stay?
I don't know
At first I thought the Real
World was run by men
And then, there was a minute,
where I thought it was run by horses
But then I realized that
horses just men extenders
Oh, I had that tree house! I
saved up my allowance to buy it.
I've never seen a car like that
before. What happened here?
Everything, basically everything, exists to
expand and elevate the presence of men!
- That's amazing
- Beautiful.
- I know
- Barbie's here
Ken?
What have you done?
What are you wearing?
Don't question it, just
roll with it, tiny baby
Don't call me baby
What about mini baby?
Like this mini fridge?
No, Ken
This is my Dream House.
It is MY Dream House!
It's mine!
No, this is no longer
Barbie's Dream House
This shall henceforth be known as
Ken's Mojo Dojo Casa House
- You don't have to say dojo and house
- And casa
But you do because
it feels good. Try it
- Mojo Dojo
- No, don't... don't say it
Mojo Dojo Casa House
Give it to me straight.
How weird is it?
Whoa, boss. These Mojo Dojo Casa
Houses are literally flying off the shelves
The kids are clamoring for 'em
Ken is on t-shirts, mugs...
- It's the number 1 tattoo
- Oh no
Warner Bros has started
auditions for the Ken movie
Which is already
a blockbuster hit
It's happening. The thing
we could never imagine.
- And if we don't get my work lady...
- "Executive assistant"
My executive work lady and someone
who's probably her daughter back here
and close the portal, our
worlds could be altered forever
So what does it matter if it's Barbie
or Ken? The money is pouring in
Shame on you, Executive Number 2
You think I spent my entire life in
boardrooms because of a bottom line?
No! I got into this business
because of little girls and their dreams
In the least creep way possible
Now blade faster! Time is running out
Look, I'm just having some brewski
beers at my Dojo Mojo Casa House
- Ken!
- You can stay if you want
As my bride-wife.
Or my long term, low
committment distance girlfriend
- Ugh!
- What do you say?
Brewski beer me?
I will not brewski beer you
That's fine
You know now that you Barbies
aren't around to run everything
We can do our
hair however we like
I have hats
Where are my hungry
boys?  Who wants snacks?
Barbie, I am so happy to see you.
Can you believe what is happening?
I know, isn't it great?
Anyone need a brewski beer?
What are you
doing? You're a doctor!
I like being a
helpful decoration
And Alan likes to help me
give all the Kens foot massages
No I don't... I don't like that
We love it!
- Ugh, so gross
- I'm so blotto face day drunk right now
Ditto, same... same that
I like not having to make any
decisions. It's like a spa day for my brain
Forever
What is wrong with them?
We just explained to them
the immaculate, impeccable,
seamless garment of logic that
is patriarchy and they crumbled
Oh my god, this is like in the 1500s
with the indigenous people and smallpox
They had no defenses against it
Yeah!  Buckle up, babe
Because Barbie Land...
...is now Ken Land
And it's going to be just like
Century City in Los Angeles
Because they had it all
figured out in Century City
The minute you get
out of your car, you're like
"I can't believe how
great this place is!"
No no no, they don't
have it figured out in Century City
Because we failed them
No, you failed ME!
Out there I was somebody
And when I walked
down the street...
...people respected
me just for who I am
One lady
She even asked me for the time
- No way!
- Way
And if it weren't for
these technicalities like...
MBAs, medical degrees,
and... I don't know...
...swim lessons, I
could've ruled that world
But I don't need any
of those things here
Here I'm just a dude
And you know what?
That's enough
TV remote?
Which one is it?
Oh, it's that one right there
Call me Mr. Ken President
Prime Minister Man
Let's recap all the amazing changes
and innovations thanks to the Kens
The Nobel Prize in horses...
Goes to... Ken!
Ken! Ken! Ken! Ken!
Wow
And now you're making
it permanent with a
special with election to
change the Constitution
That's right, in just 48
hours all the Kens will
head to the polls and vote
to change the Constitution
To a government for Kens,
of the Kens, and by the Kens!
You can't do this
This is Barbie Land. The
Barbies worked hard
and they dreamed hard to
make it everything that it is you-
You can't just undo it in a day
Literally and
figuratively watch me
Now...
If you'll excuse me
This is my Mojo Dojo Casa House
It's not...
Barbie's Mojo Dojo Casa House
Right?
How's that feel?
It is not fun, is it?
It's Boys' Night!
Every night is Boys' Night.
Barbie! Take your
lady fashions with you!
Take your Celebrate Disco Bell Bottoms
And your Icecapade Pretty
Practice Suit and Dazzling Show Skirt
- These are archival
- Your Pajama Jam in Amsterdam set!
And your Pretty Paisley Palazzo Pants!
- Not the Palazzo!
- And get out!
Leave the skirt!
Honey
Why did you wish me to your
messed up world using your
...complicated human
thoughts and feelings?
- What?
- Barbie Land was perfect before
I was perfect before
I'm so sorry, I... I wasn't
trying to do anything
Don't apologize
Don't blame my mom
Oh Sasha, that's sweet
Maybe you wished us.
Maybe it's your fault, Barbie.
No, I didn't wish anything.
I never wanted anything to change
Oh, honey, that's life
It's all change
Well that's...
That's terrifying
I don't want that
Not my life. No thank you
Just... no. I don't want this
I'm just going to sit here and wait
and hope that one of the more...
...leadership oriented Barbies just...
...snaps out of it, does
something about this whole mess
I really understand this feeling
It's basically like being a
human person all the time
Please just leave me
here, just leave me, go back
to your messed up world
and just leave me to mine?
- So you're just going to give up?
- Yes.
Okay
You know I almost feel bad for you, but you
are exactly what I thought you were
Um
Let's go, honey, let's just...
- Okay, how do we even...
- Do everything we did in reverse
Unbelievable
Come on, mom. She
doesn't deserve you
This is the lowest
I've ever been
Emotionally and physically
Okay kids, it's time to run out
and get the new Depression Barbie
She wears sweatpants
all day and night
She spent 7 hours
today on Instagram
Looking at her estranged
best friend's engagement photos
While eating a family
sized bag of Starbursts
And now her jaw is
killing her and she's going
to watch the BBC's Pride and Prejudice
for the seventh time
until she falls asleep
Our families is such that
any alliance between us
must be regarded as a highly
reprehensible connection
Anxiety, panic attacks,
and OCD sold separately
Barbie, Barbie. Wake up
I'm like you now
Ugly and unwanted
Thanks
Let's get her in
the back, come on
- Isn't this great?
- Yes
- Wait until you see the boat
- The boat
Beautiful countryside
He said he could see through me
I spent four years
prostrate to the higher mind
Got my paper and I was free
I went to the doctor,
I went to the mountains
I looked to the children,
I drank from the fountains
We interrupt to this broadcast
to bring you our new radio station
Only playing Ken's favorite song
Turn this song off, for Christ's sake!
- Who are you?
- I'm Alan
- Oh you are Alan, that's great!
- Don't tell the Kens, I'm trying to escape
I cannot sit on one more leather
couch. It's going to break my spirit
As soon as they figure out how to
build that wall sideways and not just up
No one is going to
be able to get in or out
So we want to leave,
we'd better make a run for it
No Alan, you can't go
Having a Barbie in
the Real World is what
caused all these
problems in the first place
Not one person would care
if Alan was in the Real World
In fact, it's happened before
All of NSYNC, Alan
Yes, even him. So come on!
Hey, you there!
- What... what do we do?
- Just get in the car and keep it singing
Hey man! Be ready for anything
- Who are you?
- I'm Alan
I'm uh... I'm Ken's buddy.
Yeah. All his clothes fit me
Get in the car
- Wait, you don't have a driver's license
- Well this car doesn't have an engine
Fine
KINGDOM OF KEN
- What are you doing? We gotta go
- We have to go back
Barbie Land needs
saving. Barbie needs saving
Wh... you hate Barbie
But you don't. You've always
believed in what she could be
Yeah, well, I was wrong.
Barbie gave up. The Kens won
You have to try. Even if...
Even if you can't make it
perfect, you can make it better
I can't make anything
better. I'm the one who ruined
Barbie Land with my stupid
drawings in the first place
They're not stupid,
they're amazing
You like my drawings?
They're weird and dark and... crazy
Everything you pretend not to be
I am.... I am. I'm weird
and I'm dark and I'm crazy
Easy. Easy...
Okay
- Do you want some more Alan?
- No!
- We have to get out of here right now
- Shut up, Alan!  We're going back
Let's go get my doll
I'll never get out of here
Where do we find Barbie?
There's only
one place she'd be
You're a writer
This is your Nobel prize.
Remember winning it?
It's useless trying to deprogram
her, I already did everything I could
Oh my god
I don't even know how I got here
I don't deserve this
Um, I'd like to thank...
Ken
Thank you, Ken
I love you, Ken
The fork in my soup
is this Barb...
Why didn't the
brainwashing work on you?
My exposure to the Real World
must have made be immune
Either you're brainwashed
or you're weird and ugly
There is no in between
Sing it, sister
Well, get ready kids.
Because in 48 hours...
Barbie Land becomes Ken Land
Come on, gang. We'll find
Barbie at the top of these stairs
The Kens... they found us
Ken!
Ken?
Hello?
Humans. We're fine
And Alan
Come into my Weird House, hi!
I'm Weird Barbie
I am in the splits, I have a funky
haircut and I smell like basement
Oh my god, I had a Weird Barbie!
- Yeah, you did
- You make then weird by playing too hard
It's cool
That's Sugar Daddy Ken,
and Earring Magic Ken
Mattel discontinued them
- Sugar daddy?
- No no no, I'm not a sugar daddy
This is Sugar. And I'm her daddy
And I have an
earring, a magic earring
These were actual Kens
More discontinued Barbies
- Growing Up Skipper? May I?
- Okay
Watch this
- Her boobs grow!
- Why would they do that?
And Barbie Video Girl?
I have a TV in my back
You know whose dream that
is?  Nobody.  Nobody's dream
And that's Barbie
Barbie, of course
She's not dead, she's just
having an existential crisis
Okay, come on
What's wrong?
I'm not...
pretty anymore
What? You're so pretty
I'm not "Stereotypical
Barbie" pretty
Note to the filmakers:
Margot Robbie is the wrong
person to cast if you
want to make this point
But you're beautiful
It's not just that. I'm not...
smart enough to be interesting
- You're so smart
- I can't do brain surgery
I've never flown a plane
I'm not the President
No one on the
Supreme Court is me
I'm not...
good enough...
for anything
It is literally impossible
to be a woman
You are so beautiful
And so smart,
and it kills me that
you don't think
you're good enough
Like...
we have to always
be extraordinary
But somehow
we're always doing it wrong
You have to be
thin, but not too thin
And you can never
say you want to be thin
You have to say you
want to be healthy
But also you have to be thin
You have money,
but can't ask for money
Because that's crass
You have to be boss,
but can't be mean
You have to lead, but you
can't squash other people's ideas
You're supposed to
love being a mother, but
don't talk about your
kids all the damn time
You have to be a career woman, but
also always be looking out for other people
You have to answer for men's
bad behavior, which is insane
But if you point that out,
you're accused of complaining
You're supposed to
stay pretty for men, but
not so pretty that you
tempt them too much or
that you threaten other women because you're
supposed to be a part of the sisterhood
but always stand out
And always be grateful
But never forget that the system is
rigged, so find a way to acknowledge that
But also, always be grateful
You have to never get old
Never be rude, never show off
Never be selfish, never fall
down, never fail, never show fear
Never get out of
line, it's too hard
It's too contradictory and nobody
gives you a medal or says "thank you"
And it turns out, in fact,
that not only are you doing
everything wrong, but
also everything is your fault
I'm just so tired...
of watching myself and
every single other woman
tie herself into knots
so that people will like us
And if all of that...
is also true for a doll...
representing a woman...
then I don't even know
Wait...
I did write a book
It's like I've been in a dream
where I was somehow
really invested
in the Zack Snyder
cut of Justice League
But what you said
broke me out of it
- Really?
- Yeah
You're back!  She's back!
By giving voice to the cognitive
dissonance required to be a woman
under the patriarchy,
you robbed it of its power
Yes
I just said all of that
Hell yes, White Savior Barbie!
No, it was your mom.
Your mom did the saving
We have to stop the Kens
And you need to say all of
those things to the other Barbies
- That's the key
- Got it
But how are we going to get
the Barbies away from their Kens?
We have experience
with a world like this one
Do you have a
map of Barbie Land?
What do you think?
- Wow
- Thanks, I built it
Okay, here's the deal
It's not just about how they see us,
it's about how they see themselves
Ken Land contains the
seeds of its own destruction
First we have to get the
Barbies away from their Kens
We could use a decoy
Barbie who pretends
to be brainwashed.
That should be you
Distract them by appearing
helpless and confused
Kens cannot resist
a damsel in distress
You have to make them
believe that they're complacent
That they have the power.
And when their guard is down...
You take the power back
The influence that
Porsche 356 has
had on the motoring
world as a whole...
it can't be overstated
Ugh, Photoshop is so hard
I just don't understand
how to use the select tool
Honey, you can only
use the select tool if
the layer is highlighted.
Let me show you
My tiny head is just swimming
with technical jargon like...
Color bands and magnetic
lassos and bitmap
Do you think that you, with
strong arms, can explain to me...
- What's happening?
- Alan, go around
- But what about Ken?
- No no no...
- No, but I love him!
- Come on, Alan
What's going to happen to Ken?
Just listen
You have to be their mommies,
but no remind them of their mommy
Any power you have must
be masked under a giggle
What happened?
One minute I was
President and then the next
I was cutting
Ken's steak for him?
Welcome back, Madame President
Then we'll recruit the now
un-brainwashed Barbies to our cause
They can be the new decoys
You can tell them that you've
never seen The Godfather
and that you'd love
them to explain it to you
- Ooh, are you guys watching The God Father?
- The Godfather
- I've never seen it!
- Oh my god, you've never seen The Godfather?
This movie is a rich blend of
Coppola's aesthetic genius
and a triumph to Robert Evans and
the architecture of the 70s studio system
Can you just start the movie over
and just talk through the whole thing?
You have to find a way to reject a man's
advances without damaging their egos
Because if you say yes
to them, you're a tramp
but if you say no to
them, you're a prude
- I don't want to touch a foot
- No, you don't
Another one: be
confused about money
I just have all my money
in a savings account
That's totally wrong! You need
treasury bonds, corporate bonds, CDs...
No one has CDs anymore!
Ah sweetheart, you are so
cute when you're confused
But no, not music. CD
stands for certificate of deposit
Stephen Malkmus really harnessed
the cervic toxing of Lou Reed
with post-punk influences
such as Wire and The Fall.
- What am I wearing?  I would never choose this
- Because you're a physicist
- Do you want some pants?
- Yeah
Welcome back, Barbie.
Gee, I am so awkward
and don't feel pretty at all
And will anyone ever like me?
Or distract them
with the old standby
Wearing glasses so that they
can discover that you're pretty
- May I?
- Sure, go ahead
There. Now we see
your beautiful face
And then there's pretending
to be terrible at every sport ever
Here, let me show you
- Here, let me show you
Here, let us show you
We do this until every single
Barbie is deprogrammed
and ready to take back Barbie Land
Yes!
Tomorrow the Kens vote
to change the Constitution
So we have to get there first
The final stage
of our of the plan
To turn the Kens
against each other
Now that they think
they have power over you
You make them question whether
they have enough power over each other
What if this doesn't work?
What if he doesn't...
...like me anymore?
- He likes you
- He was really upset
Because he likes you
And because he
knows deep down that...
- ...you don't like him the same way
- It still doesn't mean I want to hurt him
He took your house
He brainwashed your friends,
he wants to control the government
True
- Girl
- Yeah
It's like I'm a woman already
Welcome
Is this what it's like?
- It's time
- I'm ready
Thank you
Here I go
Hi!
Oh, hey
You've caught me reading
-I've been thinking, Ken Land?
- Kendom
- Kendom Land
- Land of...
- Land of the Free and the Men
- Right, well, this place... is...
- Kendom Land
Really great
And the Kens really
are just better at
ruling than the
Barbies ever were
Well, we just took patriarchy
and, you know, made it patriarchy
- Yeah, well, I was thinking...
- Yes?
I'm ready to be your
long term distance
low committment
casual girlfriend
if you'll still have me
- Can you just hold on for one second?
- Oh, okay
Sublime!
I don't know, I'm going
to have to think about that
Oh
Please?
Okay. Come on in
- I'll play the guitar at you
- Oh, yay!
This is the final
stage of our plan
Give them their dream come true
And at the peak
of their happiness
when they think you
actually care about this song...
You take it all away
What are you texting?
- What?
- Who are you texting?
- No one
- Hm, let me just...
- Ken!
- Sorry, one sec
That's a beautiful
song that you're playing
Did you write it?
Yes. Do you want to sit
here and watch me do it
while I stare uncomfortably into
your eyes for four and a half minutes?
I would love that
Sorry, one sec
I'll be right back
You play on their egos
and their petty jealousies
and you turn them
against each other
One sec
Sorry
While they're fighting,
we take back Barbie Land
Does the title of long term distance casual
low committment girlfriend mean nothing?
- What do we do?
- We beach every individual one of them off
No
We go to war
- Against the Barbies?
- No, against the Kens
- But we are the Kens
- The other Kens
Well we should probably
call them something
else so that it
doesn't get confusing
No, because we'll
know what we mean
But when we're on the battlefield
and you "Ken at 4 o'clock"...
- ...how will I if you mean us Kens or the other Kens?
- Because my dudes, we attack at 10 o'clock
We take advantage
of the morning waves
But not so early, because
we're going to want to sleep in
But what will we fight
with? We have no guns
Tennis rackets and volleyballs
- And slap fights
- And beach offs
- Yes!
- Oh yeah
Doesn't seem to matter what I do
I'm always number two
No one knows
how hard I tried, oh-oh, I
I have feelings that I can't explain
Drivin' me insane
All my life, been so polite
ButI'llsleepalone tonight
'Cause I'mjust Ken
Anywhere elseI'd be a ten
Is it my destiny to live and
die a life of blonde fragility?
I'm just Ken
Where I see love, she sees a friend
What will it take
for her to see the man
behind the tan and fight for me?
I'll see you on
the Malibu Beach!
You can Ken, you
can Ken, you can Ken...
And now they destroy themselves
You know what I think, I think we
should put our fricken Constitution back
- Yes!
This is a real
hornet's nest in here
Watch your flank!
- I got shot
- Impossible!
- Are there real weapons here?
- No
I wanna know whats like to love
To be the real thing
Is it a crime? Am I not
hot when Im in my feelings?
And is my moment
finally here or am I dreaming?
Im no dreamer
Ken!
Can you feel Ken-ergy?
They are, you are, we are
Imjust Ken
Anywhere elseI'd be a ten
Is it my destiny to live and
die a life of blonde fragility?
Imjust Ken
Where I see love, she sees a friend
What will it take
for her to see the man
behind the tan
and fight for me?
Imjust Ken
And Im enough
And Im great at doing stuff
So, hey, check me
out, yeah, Im just Ken
My name's Ken
And so am I
Put that manly hand in mine
So, hey world, check
me out, yeah Im just Ken
Baby, Im just Ken
Nobody else, nobody else, I'm just Ken!
- Ken!
- Huh? Yeah?
- Aren't we supposed to vote today?
- What?
- To change the Constitution
- That was today, wasn't it?
Okay ladies, let's do this!
All those in favor of letting
Barbie Land, be Barbie Land...
...say "I"
I!
I'm so happy
Go, Barbie! Go, Barbie!
Is it just my imagination...
Or do these Mojo Dojo Casa Houses...
...just get dreamier?
That's because they're dreamhouses, mother------
That's right, we've reinstated the Barbie
Land Constitution to what it should be
And restored all the
Barbies' brains and autonomy
And we seriously
disinfected those houses
What do we do?
Kens?!
Who are we attacking, sir?
No
No!
Don't look at me!
Is he crying?
Just... give us a minute.
Ken?
- Are you ok?
- Yeah. Totally
It's okay if you're
crying. You know, I
cried too and it's
actually kind of amazing
I'm a liberated man, I
don't cry, he's not weak
Okay...
Do you want to
sit up for a minute?
It was hard running stuff
I didn't love it
I get it
And those mini
fridges are so small
You can only fit
a six pack in there
and the freezers
are basically useless
To be honest, when I found out
the patriarchy wasn't about horses
I had lost interest anyway
That's okay
I always thought this
would be our house
Oh...
Ken...
I think I owe you an apology
I'm really sorry I
took you for granted
Not every night
had to be Girl's Night
Thank you for saying that
Thank you
Oh, I didn't mean suggest...uhh
I just don't know
who I am without you
You're Ken
But it's "Barbie... and Ken"
There is no just Ken
That's why I was created
I only exist...
within the warmth of your gaze
Without it...
i'm just an another blonde
guy who can't do flips
Maybe it's time to
discover who Ken is.
Ok, I think I get it now
No no no no no, this isn't the answer
I feel so stupid
I look so stupid
I look so stupid!
- No!
- You look cool! You look so cool!
Okay Ken, you have to figure
out who you are without me
- Why?
- You're not your girlfriend
You're not your house,
you're not your mink
- Beach;
- Nope, you're not even beach
Maybe all the things
that you thought
made you you aren't...
...really you.
Maybe it's Barbie and...
It's Ken
Ken...
is...
- ...me?
- Yes!
Ken is me
And I'm Barbie
Ken...
...is me!
- Ken is me!
Ken is me!
I don't even care about being Ken
anymore, I just miss my friend Barbie
- That's cool
- Barbie. Barbie!
I'm right here
Ken!
I want you to have it
It's nice
We were only fighting because
we didn't know who we were
Ken is...
ME!
Ken is right
It's just so hard to be a leader
- You know...
- That's... my boss
Midge.
I thought we discontinued her
Look, you know how many times
I've wanted to stand
up in a boardmeeting
and just say "can we
just tickle each other?"
- Really?
- Let's have a company retreat and just tickle each other!
Someone get me. Someone get me
I love being tickled
No no no no no no.  Don't hug me
But thanks to Barbies,
I too can now relieve myself of
this heavy existential burden while
holding onto the
very real title of CEO
And we can restore everything in
Barbie Land to exactly the way it was
- Mr. Mattel...
- Please
- Call me mother
- No thank you
I don't think that things should go
back to the way that they were
No Barbie or Ken should
be living in the shadows
Or Alan
- Hey
- Yeah
- Hello
- I just want to say I'm sorry...
we called you Weird Barbie behind
your back and also to your face
It's okay. I'm owning it
Would you like a job in my Cabinet?
May I please have Sanitation?
- It's yours!
- Yeah, uh, thank you
- Alright
- Madame President
Please may the Kens have
one Supreme Court justice?
Oh, I can't do that
But maybe a lower circuit court judgeship...
We accept! As long as we can wear robes
Well the Kens have to start somewhere
And one day the Kens will have as
much power and influence in Barbie Land
As women have in the Real World
I don't want to...
- Just go!
- I can't!
- Grow up and go
- I have an idea
Tell me your secret dream, child
Okay, what about Ordinary Barbie?
She's not
extraordinary. She's...
not president of anything.
Or maybe she is
Maybe she's a
mom, maybe she's not
Because it's okay, to
just want to be a mom
or to want to President,
or a mom who is President
or not a mom who
is also not President
She just has a flattering top
And she wants to get through the
day feeling kind of good about herself
That's a...
- ...terrible idea
- Yeah, that's going to make money
Oh, Ordinary Barbie, I love it!
Fantastic.
- Great
- Cool
- Yeah
I think we're good, right?
Alright, let's begin the work to close
the portal between our two worlds
- And about Barbie?
-What do you mean?
What's her ending?
What does she get?
Well that's easy
She in love with Ken
That is not her ending
I'm not in love with Ken
What do you want?
I don't know... I'm...
I'm not really sure
where I belong anymore
I don't think I have an ending
That was always the point
I created you so you
wouldn't have an ending
It's you
You're Ruth from Mattel
Baby, I am Mattel
Until the IRS got to me,
but that's another movie
- So you're...
- Ruth Handler
Inventory of Barbie
That's so cool
Her ghost keeps an
office on the 17th floor
- What?
You guys, do you think the lady
who invented Barbie looks like Barbie?
I'm a 5 foot nothing grandma with a
double mastectomy and tax evasion issues
Nobody looks like Barbie
Except, of course, Barbie.
Take a bow down, honey
I don't really feel
like Barbie anymore
Come. Walk with me
Thank you
Thank you, Barbie
I'm not really sure what
I'm supposed to do now
I've always been
Stereotypical Barbie and...
and don't think I'm really
good at anything else
- You saved Barbie Land from patriarchy
- That was very much a group effort
And you helped that
mother and daughter connect
They really helped each other
Maybe you're Self-Effacing Barbie?
Maybe I'm not Barbie anymore
You understand that
humans only have one end
Ideas live forever
Humans not so much
You know that, right?
I do
Being human can be
pretty uncomfortable
I know.
People make up things like
the patriarchy and Barbie...
just to deal with how
uncomfortable it is
I understand that
And then you die
Yeah
I want to be part of the people...
that make meaning
Not the thing that's made
I want to do the imagining.
I don't want to be the idea
Does that makes sense?
I always knew that Barbie would
surprise me, but I never expected this
Do you give me permission to...
become human?
- You don't need my permission
- But you're the Creator, you...
Don't you control me?
I can't control you, anymore
than I can control my own daughter
I named you after her: Barbara
And I always hoped for
you, like I hoped for her
We mothers stand
still so our daughters
can look back and see
how far they've come
So being human's not
something I need to...
ask for? Or...
even want?  I can just...
It's something I just discover I am?
I can't in good
conscience let you take
this leap without you
knowing what it means
Take my hands
Now, close your eyes...
Now, feel
So Barbie left behind the pastels
and plastics of Barbie Land...
for the pastels and
plastics of Los Angeles
Okay. Thanks for the lift
- You've got this
- I'm really proud of you
Estoy muy orguoso de ti
Orgu-LLO-so
Orgulloso
Orgulloso de ti
There you go. Close enough
You guys are the
best. Thank you.
Okay!
S se puede!
- That's a political statement
- That's appropriation, Dad
We'll be here when you're done
We love you!
Hi
- Name?
- Oh, um
Handler, Barbara
And what are you here for today, Barbara?
I'm here to see my gynecologist