See you, Jimmy.
Everyone, thank you for coming to Mission
Impossible to Final Reckoning.
Every mission has led to this.
There are so many people are in comparable
director Krista from Macquarie.
My producing partner are fantastic and
extraordinary cast and crew.
They work very, very
hard to bring you the
most authentic cinema
experience that we could.
So we are all so happy that
you were here in this theater
to watch the biggest
mission yet on the big screen.
The way it was meant to be seen.
So please enjoy the show.
We made a few.
Thank you.
We did a die in the shadows.
For those we were close.
And for those we never made.
The end of the film is filled.
It's cool.
There they go.
This entity has multiple personalities.
This thing has a mind.
It's so fluid.
Self-realizing truth.
It's an digital parasite.
Fasting on the side.
It's amazing.
It's everywhere.
And nowhere.
And it has no situation.
We listen.
We didn't watch those.
There are too many personal secrets.
For years.
We're kind of like now, right?
Or be anyone.
in the day is not me to ta
to you to the end of the day.
And we're from home
to the end of the world.
And most of your days
and years are reached.
And you're up the
end of the world.
And most of my
heart is very strong.
And my allies and one
have been explored.
And every week we'll start
to meet these intercessors.
Some will force it to start to power.
We just stay west and everything.
The world is changing.
Truth is finishing.
All is coming.
Good evening, even.
This is your precedent.
Since you won't reply to anyone else,
I thought I'd reach out directly.
First, I want to thank you for a lifetime
of devoted and unrelenting service.
We're in not for the tireless
dedication of you and your team.
The earth would be
a very different place.
It might not even be here at all.
Every risk you take in.
Every comrade you've lost in the field.
Every personal sacrifice you made has
brought this world another sunrise.
It's been 35 years since
circumstances brought you to us.
And you were given the choice.
Since the IMF saved
you from a life in prison.
And though you never bothered
orders, you never let us down.
You were always the best of man.
In the worst of times.
I need you to be that man now.
In the months since you evaded capture in
Austria, every corner of cyberspace has
been infested by the truth-eating
parasitic AI known to us as the entity.
Under his influence, digital information
has been corrupted worldwide.
Nations and people no
longer know what to believe.
Antagonism, aggression and
martial law are the new world border.
Exploring this paranoid atmosphere,
the entity has inspired a dual-stake halt
with alkalites devoted to really the world
of corruption through human extinction.
The Lord said to Noah: "Here I am.
I send a flood upon the earth.
Let every fleshly person perish."
The children of the atom
will rise from the ashes.
The entity will help them rebuild.
These fanatists are
secretly working to infiltrate
at all levels of the security apparatus.
Governments, and our militaries.
They are dedicated to serving
their digital master's ultimate goal.
Our only hope of controlling the entity
relies on finding its original source code.
If anyone knows what we're
about of this code, it's this man.
His identity, his past, his
very existence have been
erased suggesting he is or
was in league with the entity.
Austrian authorities
have his accomplice in
custody, which he is
refused to tell us anything.
Which brings us back to you.
You are in position of a team,
believed to be a vital component in our
struggle to acquire
the entity's source code.
Yet you refuse to come in,
fearing any government will
weaponize this malicious AI
against the rest of the world.
Instead, you've resolved to
kill the entity, a reckless act
that would trigger the total
annihilation of cyberspace.
This will eradicate the
global economy, plunging
the world into war
and famine without end.
Agent Hunt, Ethan,
please surrender, where
the blood of the world
will be on your hands.
This message will
self-destruct in five seconds.
Come home, Ethan,
and bring us that key.
Hey, Ethan.
Sorry about the core.
The rich books are, but it's
dreams for you, from pillows.
Yeah, many more.
First of all, I came.
It's always been to see you
on the right side of the grass.
I'm worried you're working too hard.
Don't worry about all of them.
So, what did you
manage to find out?
Hold on.
I'm not worried of you.
So what's the play?
First, we have to find you.
How do we find you?
Wait,
wait, wait, wait, wait, you call that in.
See, I don't want to close that.
They guys.
Clark is running in.
You take us in.
There won't be anyone on earth who can
stop it.
Has a part of you to know that.
I can see it.
We've got to say, to try to get out.
It's okay, it's okay.
It's okay.
So, nations on this one.
So, arrive while you have to use no
doctor.
It's who keeps their head.
And who can it?
The entity wants you scary, wants us all
scared.
And wants us divided.
It wants you to turn us in.
Don't, don't.
It's okay.
Please, take it.
Please.
You should be in
there without backup.
Bet you, please.
We got this.
This is a terrible idea.
Just relax.
In this place is crawling
with clandestine services.
You should get out of that.
It's okay.
I don't think everyone would
risk coming to that party.
I bought.
Nothing is just so good now.
It's here.
It's gotta be here.
You think we could say goodbye?
I'm following you.
Stay with you.
The most...
Are you sure it's really new?
Oh, you're not sure.
You have fun to hurt me.
Come here.
Nice.
I didn't see you with that one.
Awesome.
It's a good people.
Okay.
We're grateful.
Gentlemen.
That's a personal.
You know, I like the long tail.
I really appreciate your coming.
But you shouldn't be here.
I didn't have much choice.
Will you expect me to be true?
I expect you to save him from
himself and the world from him.
You can't treat you.
You just got your job.
One of trouble, Greta.
The whole world's in, don't leave me.
You're the only one
I trust to save him.
So, what's the play?
Okay.
Great.
Gabriel's a good job for you, Hunt.
Ethan, wake up!
Okay.
What do we do?
Tell me you have a plan.
They took my watch.
Your watch?
- Yeah.
It might have legs.
I'd locked it similarly.
I see.
Why do I have?
Okay.
Now listen.
Let's do it.
Let's go.
Guys, look at me.
Look at me.
You're gonna get through this.
Okay, through what?
Just keep telling yourself.
It's only pain.
Stop!
Don't touch him!
You can't hurt him.
Not that way.
Take you back to Shanghai...
What was your name?
Julia.
A former Mrs. Hunt.
Did you even fail to mention that?
Something David took her.
He demanded a ransom for her.
For something only Ethan took him.
David called it the rabbit's foot.
But it has another name.
Against God.
I never told you what
was in that chemistry today.
But you always wondered.
Still in the rabbit's foot.
It was just one event.
And a lifelong pattern
repeating itself over and over.
For every life is tried to save.
It's gambled millions more.
But then down and down again.
And another fate of
every living soul on earth.
This is responsibility.
You must be exhausted.
Where's the key?
Let it go.
Then we'll discuss it.
We don't have the time.
Some of you who
close will die tonight.
For the sake of those
you will never meet.
Unless you do exactly as I say.
He also said the key would
be his own train remember.
You have one joke.
Get on the train.
Get the key.
Get off the train.
How did you most detail the news
and have found out you blew it?
You failed.
And how did he have
to use forsaken you?
You're choosing to
compromise, Jason.
I know what Luther's doing.
I know what you're planning.
Resist me and I'll
make you pay dearly.
If you cooperate.
I can help.
He says for what?
You're searching for a Russian submarine.
Vanished on its main voyage.
The K-559 is a festival.
A state of the art submarine completely
undetectable to any known sign-on.
And the secret to its
invisibility was that.
The part covert.
A counter-acoustic algorithmic drive
located in the sivastable Sinai sphere.
Now, in the winter of 2012, the Russians
discovered a computer virus of unknown
origins spreading
through their black sea flint.
A digital covert operative.
We suspect this mystery virus was only
intended to sabotage the pod-cover,
rendering the submarine detectable.
Instead, it tricked the
crew into sickle themselves.
Check it.
Or on top, it was not responding.
It's coming like that.
All the meters, all the waves, four, all
the people who set up the simulation.
If we're right, the one thing we need to
kill the entity.
It's a regional source code.
It's buried in the
sivastable solar sphere.
Somewhere deep at
the bottom of the ocean.
Frozen in time.
Where even the entity can't reach it.
Now, the pod-cover's housing was
designed to self-destruct if tampered with.
The only way to safely open it is with a
specially designed, cruciform team.
The two halves of which were held by the
sivastable spacecraft in the next zone.
They were brought from
the Dristman package.
In the spring of 2012, by in your
divisional, a man of your skills,
now is all he needs to pinpoint
that some town to the square yard.
You think I'm going to get the
source code and bring it to you.
I don't think.
I know.
I know what you go.
Then you're going to find the entity's
source code and bring it to me.
And exchange for grace.
Then I'll take control of the entity.
If you're very routinely, you let out the
rabbit's foot.
They had to go.
It wasn't a biological or chemical weapon.
It took from family life.
The file you traded for Julia
contained malicious code,
the primordial digital rules.
From which a weapon evolved.
A weapon that used
couldn't make work.
A weapon the West might
never have made on my own.
You didn't know what
you were speaking.
You never stayed.
I know why I was telling you.
I kicked out my life.
I was still in the rabbit's foot.
I could get back.
I think that's the greatest
way to say anything.
Without you even
there'd be no entity.
And if you don't find that
sub in the next few days.
This hand of the world is we know it.
And the world be his fault.
And nothing.
Look at me.
Tell me I'm wrong.
Force use.
Find that guy for me.
I bite down my mission.
I'm dead in 60 seconds.
You'll never see that short.
Don't touch him.
Spit him out.
Really he's reversed.
You won't do it.
I got nothing to lose.
The great status has you dead.
Who's gonna save her?
Spit him out.
Have you ever seen him?
You're never seen him.
I saw you biting me.
Let him be back!
Come on.
Wait, wait, wait.
Charging?
Charging.
Hey.
Hey!
Hey, what's going on?
Hey,
what's going on?
Hey, what's going on?
Great.
Oh, hey, you don't think that I would have
left them.
First of all, never let anything happen to
him.
I think I'm serious.
I mean, I was... What?
I have been hanging.
I think we're gonna have to kill you.
Yeah.
Hey, get it right by the way.
Where are you at?
We're talking about this.
Are you supposed to have a life?
Have a life.
You're supposed to have a life.
Where are you from?
You're not serious about me.
Alright, I'm here.
Now what do you want?
Good evening, Mr. Hunt.
You have questions.
The answer is answers.
But you have to let it in.
There's a new name.
If you're serious.
Again, you know this place.
The doomsday fuck.
South Africa.
You will need the end of your air.
You will let it in.
And the fate of every
living thing will be decided.
And the blink of an eye.
This is your calling.
And this thing.
I don't accept it.
You have no secrets.
You've
heard crucified the key.
What magnum of this?
The algorithm on that drive went
period with the entity source code.
Lactus the poison bill you asked for.
You plan to retrieve the one
cover from the source code.
And destroy the entity.
And that scares you.
The entity sees infinite possibility.
And this is my cover.
And you missed everything.
And like the entity in.
It is a river.
And it is coming even.
You have always done this.
The entity offers
hope for the future.
The few who survive will be stronger.
The only.
If you let it in.
If I don't.
What that?
Destroy the world.
And you just destroy yourself.
The choice is yours.
The entity's future.
Or new future at all.
That the world being saved.
All that the world.
That destroyed.
Now you.
The Jews are my.
A real, he's not cast.
He has taken steps to be in control of the
empty.
As you will see him through.
Resist me and I'll make you pay dearly.
Some of you close will die tonight.
For ten.
You know what you are needing still to
change their destiny.
You know they can't stop the invisible.
They will destroy themselves, believe they
have no choice.
They'll turn on the skull.
In four days, they will face their final
reckoning.
You're real.
It knows.
It knows all.
It depends.
It's something you're right now.
You'll take the team.
You'll take the North.
North where is the first of all.
It's the first of all.
I have to get caught.
It's the only way you get there.
If you have to receive a decompression
chamber, steal a plane, I will play.
That's what I want you to be asked.
Do you see three of them?
You did.
If we were there, remember to transmit the
court.
It's every two hours of 15 minutes on the
song again.
18 a year now.
No, I'm not.
Take care of the team.
Do you still have a question?
But what I said, please, whatever you do,
you don't matter what's still.
Yes.
Okay.
There.
Go.
Where are you going?
Thanks, sir.
Hey, I've got the Gabriel.
Harold, I'm right, well.
You know what I'm saying?
So, what's blood is there?
What?
No, we know.
How would I think it is?
Not too special, but don't even court.
I'm guessing a five or
six megaton yield enough
to turn this entire city
into a glass ash tree.
That's... not good.
Already tried.
Can't open it.
I see that Gabriel has a poison.
Bill, you might want to find me.
How do I, well, can you just harm that?
I just have to stop these nine detonators
from imploding the court.
Attach one detonator?
No imploding.
And now the pollution, they'll critical
mass.
And they'll critical mass.
No six megaton blast.
Now, it's the time we have.
No time for you to get out of here.
Maybe.
With those tools, I get these hinges off.
Even if you could get that gate open,
I still have to detach one detonator.
What do you say?
I can save the city.
But this entire network of tunnels is
going to cave in.
But, detaches that detonator.
It's going to die.
We're both on the right side of that gate.
And you know, listen, it's something I
have to do with that.
They won't live to you by accident,
Ethan.
You know why?
Gabriel needs me alive.
And if you're dying, if you're the only
one who can make another poison bill and I
am the only one who can get to that
submarine.
I'll be waiting for him.
If he has a poison bill, I'll have to
bring him to the court.
So he can get to it.
This is where you leave me.
Okay.
What are we going to do?
We're talking.
Go fishing.
This is my mission.
This is what I was born to do.
Okay.
I can't.
It's nothing you need to say, brother.
I know.
I'm right where I want to be.
Ethan, you need to hurry.
You go.
Fine, Gabriel.
Stop him.
For those who we never need.
Because actually we never need.
him.
He will use the wish.
No one will save from pity and strength.
Is he dead?
Five.
Ten.
I got to see you in the other night.
What other?
Here we are.
at the end of this trip, bros.
Like your father.
He was in the second store.
He vanished when he was seven.
He joined.
If I never had control, he found out he
had legal trouble.
He was off at the choice.
He joined the IMF.
I spent the rest of his life in prison.
Just like you, man.
Only in your case, charges murder,
I believe.
But let me guess.
You were framed.
Just like you claimed you were framed all
those years ago in Prague.
How the mission went sideways.
How you lost your whole team.
Your story at my father down as a traitor.
That's why you killed him.
That's true.
I wish you more.
You think I'm carrying that?
But I'm here for revenge?
Or what?
Clearly my father's name.
It's my name now.
No.
I'm here.
Because I know you're the reason of world
staring down the barrel at home again.
And I also know it's not the first time you
gave him what the fate of me would rest.
And none of that would matter to me.
If he'd ever once been following orders.
Thanks.
Props.
Jim.
The answer to him once you gave me is
calling on him.
And he only agreed to be at a district or
one thing he would never expect us to do.
What's that?
You forget I know you want.
I know all your IMF, my name.
When this is over?
When you're done with you?
You and me?
Well, I don't want to make any.
It's his name, I'll let you for me.
And again, he used to hope so.
While you've been out conducting your own
personal field operation, the entity has
infiltrated the nuclear command centers of
India, Israel, Pakistan and North Korea.
Today at all four hundred hours of the time,
Francis Ramsey's facility was breached.
And Tyre, nuclear arsenal is now under the
entity's command and control.
That lives on the formations with secure
nuclear arsenals.
UK, China, Russia and us.
Everything you are, everything you've done
has come to this.
The CIA black fault break in.
I'm sorry, what is a knock list?
A complete record of our covert operatives
overseas.
So this is the man who
broke into our own black
fault, who stole the
list of our own spies.
Yes.
He did return the list.
It's on the next page.
Am I reading this correctly?
The criminal bombing?
In fairness, the bomb was actually meant
to kill him.
He gassed a security briefing at the
National Intelligence Journal.
That was just two months ago.
YouTube would have been in there.
He arrived in the form of Mr. Kitridge's
aid and left as Mr. Kitridge, I believe.
This explains the handcuffs.
It's still not clear ways here,
like it or not.
What we're looking at is our means of last
resort.
Quite possibly our only hope of referring
nuclear Armageddon.
If we want to control the entity,
we have to deal with him.
Should we choose to accept?
Agent Hunt.
And I'm sorry for your loss.
Please, sit.
Let's hear it.
I need that key in the use of a ship.
Specifically in our craft carrier,
more specifically the George H.W.
Bush.
He wants the use of a six and a half billion
dollar nuclear powered military asset.
With instructions for the ships commanded
to accommodate my every request.
To do what exactly?
Use that key in what it opens to kill the
entity.
Killing the entity means the annihilation
of cyberspace.
The consequences of which are
catastrophic.
Why the hell?
What I do.
What you suggest.
Especially matter president.
You have no other choice.
There is always another choice.
Oh man.
In this case, not a good one.
It wants to move to your powers.
You're going to paranoid downward spiral.
Every nation had a chance to take their
missiles offline.
Don't trust anyone else to do that.
Your state department is warning you the
diplomatic chance of breaking down.
Everyone who still has control their
arsenal is considering the first strike.
Just like you are.
The intelligence community knows that the
entity is learning as it goes.
It's getting smarter.
It's getting stronger.
They know that we have only
72 hours before every other
nuclear arsenal on earth
is under the entity's control.
Three days before it focuses
a full force of its energy on
the toughest or secure defense
system on the planet hours.
At this point, the defense
department will have
no choice but to insist
that you open that case.
Enter the codes and launch an all-out
preemptive strike on the world's eight
other nuclear arsenals before the entity
takes control of ours.
Better president.
Either you destroy the world or the entity
does.
In any case, it is generated.
There is another choice.
You can tell me what
you know about that key
and give us the power
to control the entity.
Not a president.
Exactly.
That's what I would tell you.
Everything I know.
Everything.
You ran the CIA.
You know psychological warfare.
What you see, it doesn't look around.
We are in the entity's reality.
And I believe it's counting on you to stop
me.
If what you sign is true, how
can you be sure the entity
doesn't want us to do exactly
what you're proposing right now?
Because it knows you
would never do anything so
illogical that you would
be insane to trust me.
And that's precisely why you should.
For once, let's let the entity worry about
what we're going to do.
I'm worried about those three other
nations.
Madam president is still in control of
their arsenal.
Nations who could make and launch a
full-scale attack while he's out there
with an aircraft carrier doing God knows
what?
While he's out there trying to kill the
entity, which we all know is a terrible idea.
My man, please.
I'm asking for three days of you.
Keep the world calm.
Three days of heaven.
Let you down before.
And when the entity decides to attack
before them.
It has enough missiles to kill buildings
already.
Why hasn't it done?
Because it's a machine.
It's thinking like a machine.
Thinking.
Thinking is dictated by what it's learned
from us.
It hasn't launched because it doesn't have
total control.
It needs the world's entire time of
arsenal to guarantee the desired outcome.
A total evaluation of humankind.
And a present.
It is going to wait.
Northward, including the Operation System
targeting central London has been breached.
The United Kingdom has lost control of his
arsenal.
I will ask you one last time.
What does this all work?
I need you to trust me.
One last time.
Trust me.
I'll tell you.
When that park runs out of 72 hours.
I have a press that will invent your
responsibility.
And a present.
Sargence.
Lock him up.
You have 72 hours!
I
love your message on there.
Your witness is over.
You can tell me yourself.
After?
They made us thinking of when they gave us
the choice.
We live and die the shadows.
And as we hold close, I'm not a result of
whatever.
I know it's on your mind.
You did the right thing when you kept
picking.
You've always been on the right side,
brother.
Always.
Never forget our lives are not defined by
anyone action.
Our lives are the sum of our choices.
I have no regrets.
And these are should you.
Did Erika did the president tell you the
meaning behind this note?
No, no.
Serbia, 22nd 1996, we lost someone we
loved very much.
All because of no one in authority would
take a risk.
I'm sitting on a pug of chemistry.
Just over that horizon is Russia's only
aircraft carrier, the animal dispenser.
I have one wrong
move away from the first
shootout between two
flat-tops and four-door two.
One flinch from touching off World War
III.
And you're asking me to fly directly into
the eye of the storm?
Yes, ma'am.
What exactly are you looking for?
So, sir, short-for-sound surveillance
system.
It's a worldwide network of undersea
acoustic cables dating back to the Cold War.
If an undersea event of any significant
happens anywhere in the world,
one of these listening stations will
pinpoint that event to the square metre.
One of these sources stations will have
accorded our missing Russian submarines
impact on the sea floor in
the winter of 2012, without
ever understanding the
significance of the event.
Where's the Russians know when this
festival vanished?
They're just not exactly sure where.
Well, did I finish one?
Wait, Sissa.
Which one?
Out of all these sources stations,
picked up the event.
We know the bodies of the Sustable's crew
were covered in CX, and since they were
covered by Inuit fishermen, we're guessing
it went down somewhere in the Arctic.
A search area of roughly five and a half
million square miles, meaning the most
likely so-so station to pick it up is this
one.
And the bearings see it.
They met you at it.
The Russians don't know this.
Why haven't they just stolen the island
already?
At the same time, Matthew was a U.S.
government installation,
and over at the end
of aggression with
trigger wood or three.
But now, I'm not getting this coming.
But here, who's nowhere in a battle?
Do your friends and other walking into a
potential situation?
They knew you used to the job.
So to retrieve the entity
source code from Sustable,
means the precise coordinates
from, say, Matthew I didn't.
And a submarine, obviously.
One that's willing to take you where you
want to go.
No questions asked.
And that's assuming your friends can
actually get the coordinates.
Which respect did you transmit for 15
minutes every two hours?
In the hope that Ethan is somehow able to
receive a signal.
How do you intend to make it out from
under the ISCA?
I've turned 70-record into my 10-minute
video.
Ethan will have a VHF
transmitter, which will enable
us to zero in on his exact
location under the ISCA.
And we have to do that.
He's grab a chainsaw.
What?
Cut a hole in the ISCA and just pull Ethan
out.
Hang on.
Depending on how deep that
record, Ethan will have severe
decompression signals
before he reaches the surface.
Which is why we have this.
What the hell is that?
This is a state-of-the-art inflatable
hyperbaric decompression chamber.
You're not serious.
Oh.
You mean to tell me that Ethan's life,
the fate of all life on earth depends on
us all meeting at the
exact same place, at the
exact same time, somewhere
in the frozen baring sea.
With that.
Exactly.
And what if he drowns before we get there?
It won't likely hurt.
He will.
But in water that cold, the
hyperthermia will slow down
his metabolic functions
and by his time to revive him.
That's your plan.
Exactly.
That's a plan.
The only submarine in range is the Ohio.
Check Bloods houseboat.
Once emerged, he's reachable only by Viala
Radio.
She lived for many digital transmission.
That means he's immune to this.
But only if he's just rushed.
And as we can get you there in two hours,
but it won't have enough fuel to wait.
She's not as a choice.
If the blood so receives my command,
if he believes it to be authentic,
he might come to air-scope depths.
He might wait 30 seconds.
If you are even one minute late,
just give me this chance.
That's what I said.
With the key.
Well, it couldn't do much without it.
Somewhere in the northern Pacific I
assume.
You gave him an aircraft carrier.
I'm the commander-in-chief of the armed
forces, Mr. Secretary.
It is my aircraft carrier.
And I do with it as I please.
You knew this would happen.
I suspected you could have heard those
told us.
I just did.
And now you're excused.
Madam President.
That would be all.
I couldn't tell you.
It had to be my responsibility in mind
alone.
And I had to buy home to time.
Someone could have tried to stop him.
I may not agree with you, but they do
respect your authority.
Before this is over.
Someone will panic.
Someone will try to stop me.
Another fuel truck.
You know where he's at?
He knows where he's going to end up.
That's surprising.
This is the CIA station run
by seasoned field agents
trained to get information
and never ever give it.
Tell him nothing about our real mission.
He's got anything to talk about.
He's silly.
Hello.
Can I help you?
I certainly hope so.
Yes, we're looking for the sources
listening station.
You found it, friend.
I'm a station chief.
You'll download my wife to be sent.
Hello.
How do you do?
Nice to meet you, though.
There were searches for the British
seismologist.
Sorry, did you say Don Long?
That's right.
William Don Long.
Langley Don Long.
Black Vault Don Long.
At the same.
And you are.
I don't believe.
This guy is a coding legend.
He designed the CIA mainframe of Langley.
The black vault is the most secure
database on the planet.
It's completely dependable.
Well, if it were impenetrable,
I wouldn't be here.
The vault was breached in 96, and the
agencies should be on the same day.
And here ever since.
So you mean to say you've been on this
island for 30 years.
Just got a curiosity.
How do you know about the black vault?
That's how the class of life.
Sorry.
Who did you say you were?
Just tell the man while we're here.
Mr. Don Longville,
even if we could tell you
the truth, you wouldn't
believe that I wouldn't.
Great.
The heart of the matter
is that we need access
to all your social status
from late winter 2012.
Otherwise, the world will cease to exist
in a few days.
It's happening, isn't it?
The entity.
I tried to warn people about it for years,
but no one would listen.
Can you help us?
I wish I could.
Come in.
Make yourself comfortable.
Wake up, sir.
We got problems.
What's happening?
At the end of our business side.
We got to get out of here.
We're in our distress zone, man.
We want to be able to get us back to the
building.
Maybe you have a radio.
Nothing but static on BHF.
Your friends are broadcasting a signal.
We can't hear it.
Thank you, sir.
You're in your harbor.
We're at Bingo.
Bye, bitch.
Mr. Biff.
Please.
We can give you one.
Please now.
You must be captured by that, sir.
And you must be out of your mind.
What exactly was the plan, if we hadn't
shown that?
You know?
I really hadn't thought that far ahead.
You're at Long daily, since you're
regards.
She told me to expect a green flare.
She never mentioned the taser.
Mind telling me what this is all about.
I'm missing this classified.
I need you to take me north.
Continue.
I'm expecting a set of exact coordinates.
We have more scope transmission.
And just how exactly do you expect to
receive them down here?
You have to come in first-code death.
Raise the antenna.
Signal scandal.
We'll either do the EHF bed.
Or how long?
15 minutes.
It would give the Russians 15 minutes to
pinpoint our location.
Starting at noon every two hours after
that.
Until my team sends me those coordinates.
North is the bearing
seat, Mr. Right now every
submarine in the Russian
Pacific fleet is up there.
My primary mission is to lock down their
positions and ascertain what they're up to.
I'm thinking you know the answer.
Yes, Jack.
That's St. Matthew Island.
There's nothing there but an old source of
listening station.
That right next to me.
What is that?
That's a little sharic.
You know what that is.
It's many sure Russian special forces.
Get yourself a gold star,
Mr. Area Recon spotted
an off-sync Matthew
Island just over an hour ago.
It's deployed from this.
The bug arrived.
The deadly submarine in the Russian Navy.
My secondary mission is to locate that
bastard and hold it at risk.
The lestjaric means it's somewhere close
by.
You have people on that island.
That's where your coordinates are coming
from.
Well, you help me.
Mr. If you want to build the bear.
Oh, you've come to the right man.
Like speakers here, Dave, Mr. Sir.
Yes, sir.
That builds me in our guests in the four
common quarters.
Nice.
This way, sir.
As I've explained to our friends here,
I don't have the data they want.
The agency ignored my request to upgrade
our system for a decade.
One day, a team shows
up unannounced and
refixed the entire system
in a matter of days.
I'm guessing this is the winter of 2012.
And the old system ran on magnetic tapes
backed up to 8-inch flopies.
These were the dog set out back.
And these boxes might contain the
coordinates you're all looking for.
But, I don't have a reader.
That was also taken away in 2012.
You expected to build one.
I came for coordinates.
Not boxes.
Supposing you find the coordinates.
When I was to my team, we'll take the
coordinates to my superiors.
My man weighs here.
When we have located what we're looking
for.
My man will leave and he will not be
harmed.
Would you believe that if you were me?
No, I would not.
You have one hour to build a drive.
What's your name?
Gabs off.
Your first name?
Captain.
Cots off.
I'm Grace.
That's Benji.
Could we just for five minutes be human
beings?
Not Russians, not Americans.
Just people that want to see our loved
ones again.
I have no one.
Another than a dog.
Why are you sending you down half this
key?
A cruciform key that grants the holder
access to the Podcova.
Even if you have the
coordinates, you still can't safely
retrieve the entity's source
code without our help.
You have another key.
Don't you?
You've had one a little long.
But you don't have other coordinates.
And when you build a drive, we will have
that.
Hey, let's try something else.
What if I told you that we have a friend?
Has been disavowed by his own government
because he refused to hand over this key.
Our friend is out there right now,
independent from any chain of command,
waiting for us to transmit those
coordinates.
And he will stop at nothing
to safely retrieve the Podcova
and use the source code
stored on it to destroy the entity.
I love the sake of any one
nation, but for all, don't you
see if the entity is counting
on us to distrust each other?
Please, let us complete our mission.
We are not enemies.
We should believe that, if you want me.
I suppose I wouldn't.
You'll have one hour.
This is a marked sudden pressure suit,
specifically designed to reduce
decompression time after diving for found
deaths.
It does this by means of an exotic mixture
of oxygen and inner gases.
You'll need to do an extended grief up for
your body to handle it.
Exactly what kind of gas is your reach out
about.
Nice classified.
Assuming you're on task for
20 minutes or less, your time
in decompression will be
cut down from days to hours.
Theoretically, theoretically, we haven't
tested the mark 7 below 300 feet.
To conserve air, you'll need to make a
fast descent, which means guaranteed HPNS,
high pressure nervous syndrome.
You should expect tremors, shapes, dizziness,
disorientation, and mental confusion.
And all of it under extreme pressure.
Even if the mark 7 works
as designed, you still
won't have enough
mixture for a slow ascent.
That means you're guaranteed to get the
beds.
Magicing in your muscle tissue expands
into your bloodstream.
You screw your shitting pain.
Confulsions.
Sleep loss in muscle control.
You'll have maybe 20 minutes to get to the
decompression chamber.
What did that mean?
It was at the decompression chamber.
You're dead now.
Another VHF scan came and went.
If your friends are broadcasting,
we still haven't picked it up.
Come on, come on, come on, come on,
come on.
That's the sled dogs out in the bar.
It's coming at the dinner time.
A military or a military friend.
There are no coordinates on any of these
disks.
That refit 14 years ago.
It had all the stench of a cover-up.
And the top man talked down to the piece.
I didn't like that.
I never told them about these backups.
And when they left, I went through every
one of them myself.
A lone event stood out.
A massive undersea implosion.
Not a month before they arrived to take
everything away.
Naturally, I didn't understand the
significance.
But I noted the coordinates.
And then I destroyed the only disk.
But you see, you know where the suffice to
fall is.
Down the square meter.
Dinner time.
Can my wife please tend to the dogs?
I can't concentrate with this record.
Who call my dignity?
Not legally.
I'm just going to help you.
She's gonna need some help.
Okay.
I can use the air.
Sign up for what I did, you shut.
Five minutes to the next broadcast window.
We'll be under the ice cap soon and lose
all comms.
This will be our last chance.
Chief of the Watch.
Raise number one comms at 10.
Wait, what is this?
What is this?
You won't stop the entity.
I can't let you.
What's this?
I don't get to the radio.
We
have yet more scotting time.
Radio and speaker.
We're gonna have a good day.
Hey, dark.
Is the too much?
Dark.
What's the end of that?
That's two thousand miles off the Cape of
Good Hope on the other side of the world.
Damn near exactly.
And that's right.
Exactly.
The opposite.
In case the Russians were listening.
There we go.
Officer of the deck, set a new course.
340, right 15 degrees.
Runner, steady, of course, 340.
I saw my letter was right 15.
Officer of the deck.
Submer its contact, varying one,
zero, zero.
On the edge of our star of baffles.
You're good?
The exhibiting tolls.
The progression that's here to cast up,
we're really new to watch.
Station the fire control track and party
side.
Inside the ice server, those one must have
accomplished.
We found the belt around.
It's a rudder-nirus.
Every emergency was taking you.
Now you're taking the Russians there.
And the burning of my destination.
All the reasons for crewmen, so like if
it's with ten knots, turn this boat around
and take the Russians back the way we
came.
I haven't seen your mission there.
I'll be getting off the turn.
Mr. I thought I'd take a person chamber
you'll die for sure.
Sure.
Your decompression chamber was never part
of our plan.
Okay.
What exactly is your plan?
Give me a hand.
If it did.
No?
No, no, no, no, no... I can't.
I don't have a plan anymore.
Of course.
This should be.
What's this for?
What?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Hold back.
Take a moving.
Are you mean after day?
Take a deep breath.
Mark 7's guidance system will take you to
your coordinates.
The debt to your location is 500 feet.
Figure 19 minutes to your target 10
minutes on task.
Remember any longer than that in your
chances of survival decrease by the second.
And don't forget, you must exhale
continuously as you rise to the surface.
Hold your breath and your lungs will
explode.
The VHF transmitted us for.
Your team should be able to locate you
within a two-mile radius.
Look after that.
Good luck.
Take care of my suit.
Sir, I have near-field effect too close to
tell.
The new hurrying.
Slow to 10 knots by log.
Helm on my mark right full rudder.
Stand in by for your more captain.
The turn.
I'm sir, my rudder is right full.
I'm on the way!
What are you saying?
I'm in the back
of my You did it.
You did it.
So loud it's gone.
But how many?
I can't real.
I can't do this.
We can't do this, but we can't.
We can't real.
We can't real, did you?
Yeah, man, you're thinking.
How could we not do this against you,
start?
If we can control it, maybe we should
break the want of the break.
Praise.
All that earth, was you ever trust with
that much power?
Will you, of course?
I hate you.
I believe you are meant to do this.
That's right.
Not anyone.
You're breaking me, man.
I think so.
See you in the story.
We haven't been formally introduced.
I'm way down low, mainly.
About 30 years ago.
Almost.
So you and him.
I understand how you're in my life.
I know how to make men's food.
I've done yours.
That's a matter of perspective,
friend.
If you hadn't broken the vault 30 years
ago, I probably still be there.
I probably don't think I was happening.
I never would have found the only home
that's ever brought me in peace.
And I certainly never would have met the
woman I love.
There's nothing to be sorry about.
I owe you my life.
It'll be landing just as the clock runs
out.
By the time we arrive, the entity will
have control of the world's nine automated
doomsday arsenals, and it will be fueling
the missiles and controls.
But it can't launch until it has a safe
place to hide.
If it wants to survive.
The safest place is here.
What is that?
The doomsday fault.
How go you are?
It's a top secret standalone solar power.
Tempest hardened level A X abide data
server.
One billion gigabytes of storage.
So our home movies are far off.
It contains all the accumulated knowledge
deemed worthy of preservation.
And it's fully sealed.
Totally impervious to electromagnetic
energy of any kind.
No transmissions in our eyes.
An imperruptible art of human history
built to survive the ending of the world.
So if the entity got in there,
it could survive thousands of years,
no matter what happened to the rest of the
world.
What do you want to survive?
What does it stand the game from wiping
out all life on earth?
A question Noah and his family must have
asked just before the flag.
The entity got things as God.
Come on, Chief.
Always right to the point, aren't you?
This is the poison pill containing the
earth as algorithm.
And this is the part cover containing the
entity's original source code.
When combined, they will form a sort of
digital toxin.
When uploaded to
cyberspace, this toxin will attack
the entity and alter its
ability to perceive reality.
So combine that with the part cover,
we could deceive the Lord of lies.
May, get to your own name.
May, we don't have Luther's poison pill.
Gabriel does, which is why we can be sure
to be waiting for us in the doomsday form.
Once the entity is infected with Luther's
algorithm, it will think it's entering the
junction central data server when it will
actually be going here.
What is it?
Careful, it's very delicate.
It can't be.
It's a 5D optical data drive.
360 terabytes in the palm of your eye.
I thought these were just theoretical.
They were.
I definitely felt one.
If the entity is our
genie, then this optical
drive is the bottle
we'll capture it in.
Which brings us to the truth part.
Once inside, once it
believes that it's safe,
the entity will initiate
a nuclear launch.
We have to disconnect this drive before it
can do that.
How long do we have?
Roughly?
100 milliseconds to thank you for now.
If you do it too soon, we won't trap the
genie in the bar.
If you do it too late.
We won't prevent the entity from
launching.
Yeah.
Either way.
If we pull the drive at the wrong time,
the entity wins.
Don't show us.
How long?
If the doomsday
vault is electronically
shielded, how does the
entity expect to get in?
It expects us to let it in.
Just like Gabriel expects me to hand off
the bar of power.
Neither would you ever do, obviously.
Right?
Think about it.
The vault is electronically shielded.
No signals get in or not.
Someone has to go
outside the vault in order
to upload Luther's
poison pill to the entity.
And if Gabriel wants to control the entity,
he has to upload Luther's poison pill.
You're not seriously
going to give him the
park over and let him
get away with the pill.
That's exactly what I'm going to do.
Gabriel will be part of the team and never
know what to do.
That's insane.
You're letting the entity into the vault.
That's precisely what it wants you to do.
It is right here.
Yes.
As you only chose, we have a beating
Gabriel.
Have the entity.
When John's in a trillion.
Ethan, think about what you're doing.
Think about how you got here.
Think about how the world got here.
How do you know that the entity didn't
want you to recover the pot over?
Maybe it told you it was
impossible because it
knew that was the thing
that you needed to hear.
How would you think of it?
I think you're risking the fate of the
world and billions of lives.
I'm a bit of a liar.
Yes, right.
I am.
If there was another choice, I'd dare you.
I know you all have your doubts and I don't
blame you, but we have to stick together.
And we have to make sure that grace is the
one to disconnect that drive.
Me?
What separates could pay pocket from a
great one?
Timing.
Thank you for that.
The entity is moving now.
Matter of President, Hunt is gone.
If he isn't dead, the Russians have him.
If we lose control of
our arsenal, we lose any
hope of preventing the
entity from launching.
We are out of time.
General Sydney.
What is our most limited attack option?
Surgical nuclear strikes can
find strictly to the command
centers of the eight nations
under the entity's control.
Beijing is now about London.
Moscow, New Delhi, Paris, Pyongyang and
Tel Aviv.
Casualties.
Estimated death tolls from initial
strikes.
And more later, of course, from resulting
nuclear fallout.
Estimates vary.
Obviously, the bombing of
major cities in eight different
countries would create an
unprecedented political crisis.
One would likely lead to a protracted
global more.
It may be diplomatically prudent to make a
gesture.
A gesture.
Sacrifice one of our cities here at home.
We've prepared a list.
Cities have been raised by strategic and
economic importance and population,
of course.
You'd be sacrificing a hundred million
lives.
To save seven billion.
This can't be happening.
But in person, we are in the entities
reality now.
And this is jigmy.
The military soldiers, and their side on.
So, you heard me say, hand it over.
The military is over.
The rest of you, you just wait here.
Don't hand it over.
If you like to.
Someone wants to get lost.
It's too early to survive.
It's too exposed.
It's too close to the others.
The gate brings the night you kill you.
It has to leave you with the bill and the
vodka.
I'm respectable.
Either of you are.
That's right.
Take care of you, Tim.
I'm now let's go of that button and the
entity has no place to heart.
But what happens to you?
I have a plan that'll take me to minimum
safety systems.
Reliable, animal law.
I'm not afraid of it.
I've been by this man.
Just in case.
And you honestly believe destroying this
place will stop the entity from much.
I think it's bluffing.
Alone in the world if
you can't survive, and
you can't survive
if you don't let it in.
I hand over the vodka and I let you walk
away.
Why would I believe that?
Because I want you.
And everyone you care about.
To live long lives in the world I create.
And the entity answers to me.
You'll be using it not today, some other
place, some other time.
As long as I have this, wherever I go,
you will follow.
And the vodka will come to me.
That is written.
Nothing is written.
I'm not sure it is written.
Now, tell me I win.
You win.
I like the sound of it.
Say it again.
Uh-huh.
And why don't you dig it?
10.
10?
18 minutes.
I don't know you.
Don't love.
William, don't love.
My wife.
It's a piece of it.
I really hand it to you, huh?
This is one of Crocker, Jackie.
You let you put together.
I'm imagining the entity is shaking at its
virtual shorts right up now.
What do I need to know about this?
And what exactly was the play?
I think players give that to him and let
him go right now.
You want me to give this to him and let
Right now.
The president of the United States is
preparing to vaporize millions upon
millions of souls, only
because even here doesn't
believe that anyone can
safely control the entity.
Does that sound the same to anyone?
Maybe you should ask the crew for the
semester bomb.
10?
17 minutes.
You wouldn't be here if he didn't have a
plan.
Whoever tells me what that
plan is when we spend millions
of lives, and you'll be
spared the fate of the others.
So we're running out of time.
We need to get to a minimum safe business
while we're still standing here.
Because he's here, and he's here.
And this means something.
Any second now, Ethan's going to tell me
what it is.
I've known this man for a long time.
And he won't want anything to happen to
his precious team.
That's the pattern, isn't it?
He refused to sacrifice the ones who hold
close.
That is why we're still here.
It's over.
There's no shame.
I'm just... Tell me
what I'm missing.
Damn.
Get him!
Get the pills!
Look at the silver and the next here!
What's bigger than that?
You want to get in the bones?
The new keel bones.
What bigger than that?
Ethan!
Come!
I got this!
That's what he's got in there.
There you go, bricks.
It's your turn.
It'll
be a way to disarm it.
Even if you can prevent it
from going nuclear, there's
still no way you can stop
those detonators from exploding.
Can we survive the blast from the server,
though?
I'll use someone who stays behind and
stops the bomb from going critical.
But whoever that is, they're not going to
make it.
Keep heavy, huh?
A killer boy.
We'll handle the bomb.
The rest of you can bend you to the server
room.
There's no time to discuss it.
Go!
I'll stay with them.
There's another community doing the server
room.
Good luck.
How did you learn to do this?
I never said I did.
Good luck.
Oh, no, this is not good.
Why is that?
If I had to guess it's a potential name of
Thorax.
What does that mean?
Where's your building in the pearl cup?
My lung is glass.
If we don't act fast, it means saucation.
Oh, God, I had grass.
Do either of you have any medical
experience.
Have you seen a tree?
You got to work with him.
Christ, I need you to hack the server so
we can let the head steer.
Grab the tools, head to the power.
Here's two other ones.
A good one.
First, I need you to plug the blow.
We can anti-peel them.
Bondage.
Bondage, save a blade.
I
need you to divide the power switch now.
To the servers in jukeling that one.
Got it.
Christ, I'm gonna cover you.
Go, go, go.
The other block.
That's it.
What's up?
If the person survived.
Oh, Christ.
Oh, my God.
Spirit, don't say.
This is up a lot.
Christ, it's okay.
Yeah, but you shut it off.
Well, that's something better.
What's that, it's the answer.
All right.
You see?
Oh, everything's under control here.
Okay.
Hope is very steady.
But don't pull it out.
It's like I said, he threw.
As long as I have to kill the park over
will come to me.
These ground wires are triple redundant.
If we cut any three of
them simultaneously,
we get to lay these
detonators from exploding.
Maybe long enough for someone to make it
to the server run.
Oh, 10 seconds.
Maybe.
You think you can make with that door in
10 seconds.
I'm only to find out.
I'm in the restroom.
Okay.
We're not out of the woods yet.
Any minute now my blood pressure is gonna
drop drastically and I'm gonna go fake.
So we need to work fast.
Let's receive her in the tool bag.
The server blocks two lights on it.
Got it.
We need to splice that into the server's
solar panels.
It can untamble.
That way we'll know where anything's
uploaded in the poison tower.
Yeah.
Got it.
Okay.
Now this is the really tricky part.
There is a bundle of blue, black,
and red cables in the lower right corner.
Oh, I want to be there.
I'm gonna need you to cut through the
wires.
I'm gonna specifically go in the back.
Whatever you do.
Do not.
Color.
Fangit!
It's a regular set.
Madam President, as you secretary of
defense, I direct your attention
toConplant 8044, selected to tack option
9.1.
A targeted nuclear strike
on the command centers
of all eight nations now
controlled by the entity.
A mandate to include the American City of
chosen to sacrifice.
The disco.
And he's pulling your son.
What, what I tell you?
What?
Authentication could've been for me.
Come on, Ethan.
No way you've been.
Any minute now your two will be dead.
And the entity will have no place to hide.
I am the entity who lies here to me.
It's only a matter of time.
Grace, we think we can
perfect this bond for one
nuclear, but all of these
dead natives are with his flow.
Have a good blast.
It's been a pleasure talking.
Big.
Ethan, he's all the time we can give him.
Do not make the last cut until we
absolutely have to.
Madam President.
Launch is now enabled.
What are you doing?
What we should have done in the very
space.
What a U.S.
treaty to command center.
To cut their power.
To come, Mrs. offline entirely.
Sure, there's anything down.
Madam President, that would give the
country a completely defenseless.
But deny the entity access to the largest
entity in our smaller world.
Now, make the call.
Now, we are the only nation on earth with
the power to attack the entity.
Now, we're the only nation in the world
with the power of choice.
Today, I choose not to attack.
Not a President.
Think this through.
You are making a terrible mistake.
The sake of the country, please.
Listen to Reese.
I was asking him what I'm doing.
Connecting with strategic command agent.
No, it's the people who die, man.
If you don't push that button.
Millions of other people who die.
If she does, what gives us the right to
decide?
Who lives in U.S.?
We took an oath.
As President of the United States
launched, none of that won't matter.
Nothing won't matter.
I'm inclined to agree.
I'm afraid that I'll deal with his
entities.
Prepare to attack, man.
You may choose to live in the entities
where we have a teacher.
I don't.
Vote for the President.
General Oakton's office strategic command.
General Oakton, this is the President.
Call you from up with the authority that
has command.
I need you to listen to my instructors who
are usually funded.
I'm sorry.
Do you know who he is?
It's still me feeling it's myself,
man.
But it still needs to play style before it
launches.
It's hard to regret.
I've got it.
It's done.
We'll see this connected.
Okay.
Here we go.
We're going to switch the power back off.
We'll see if it's activated.
Red light is on.
Take off.
How are we doing?
Great.
We're starting to let's get here.
We're ready to get the fuses.
Four minutes on the clock.
Understood.
Four minutes.
Let's start the drive.
Ready.
Now you're going to watch the lights on
the receiver.
When the red lights was... Ah!
Wait, what's that?
When the red light was green?
Your noise is connected to the felt of a
pokoma.
And the answer to your spoon, thanks to
resources, all throughout.
Okay, then what?
Then?
You're going to cut that red wire and let
the answer in.
What we need now is to fill it together.
Let's take a look.
We're almost out of time.
At 10 seconds, I'm going to come backwards
from three, two, one, cut.
And we were like hell for that door.
Remember?
And then drive next time.
You know the answer is inside.
You have 100 milliseconds.
This is where I said it.
He did it.
That was sort of a badge.
That was short.
You can see this life is not some quirk of
fate.
This is what you're calling.
You're destiny.
You're destiny that touches every living
thing.
Like you're not your masters of our fate.
Nothing... It's raining.
And our cause.
However, rages, chaos and vampires,
to the impact of
our inner hope for a better future,
comes from willing that future and to be a
future reflecting the measure of good
within ourselves.
And all that is good inside us.
This measure worth good.
We do fathers.
We all share the same fate, the same
future.
There's some of our infinite choices.
Once as future is built on kindness,
trust, and we to understand.
To do something.
Driving without question.
Towards the light we cannot see.
Not just for those we are all close.
But for those we'll never meet.
I hope you know how always love you
brother.
And I will see you again.
I hope it's not too soon.
The world still needs you.
But we do.
We live and die.
This message will self-destruct in five
seconds.
Good luck, Ethan.