Well, ladies and gentlemen,
this is your captain, Rusty Griswold.
Hope you've enjoyed your 18-minute
flight from South Bend.
We'll be touching clown at Chicago's
Midway very shortly.
We'd like to thank you for flying
with us today...
...because at Econo Air, we're working
hard to win back your trust.
- Harry, you mind taking over while I hit the lav?
-Sure thing, Rusty.
Thank you very much.
- Oh, and Rusty.
-Mm-hm.
I wanna thank you for going to bat
for me last week.
I was happy to do it.
Just because corporate says
you're too old to fly doesn't make it true.
You're more qualified than us younger guys.
- Means a lot to me.
-Sure thing.
- Oh, and Rusty.
-Mm-hm.
I wanna thank you for going to bat
for me last week.
Yeah.
You bet.
Dad, is that the pilot?
It sure is.
- He just came from the cockpit.
-Whoa.
- Hey there, little guy.
-Hi.
Is this your first time on a plane?
We were planning on driving...
...but, uh, Tyler here has been begging us
to go on his first airplane.
- Oh, is that right?
Uh-huh.
Do you think I can be a pilot
when I grow up?
Heh. Yeah, well, I don't see why not.
You just have to study hard
and listen to your parents, all right?
- Okay, heh.
-Sorry about that.
- Little bit of rough air.
-it's okay.
Yeah, yeah.
Don't worry about it, heh.
Hey, we call that "turbulence," all right?
That's when the plane passes--
So sorry.
Okay, you folks enjoy the rest of your flight.
Let me give you a hand.
Can you please stay the fuck away from us?
Harry, you took us up to 60,000 feet.
What are you doing?
Oh, Rusty.
I wanna thank you for going to bat
for me last week.
Or the time that Pan Continental put us up
at the Ritz in Barcelona.
You know, I'll tell you one thing
about the Spanish women:
- They, uh, love them some airline pilots.
-Heh. They do.
I never took the uniform off,
except when I did.
Ladies.
All full. You have to wait for the next one.
- But I was...
-You were what?
I'll catch the next one.
See you around, Econo Air.
- The third time this month.
- I know.
Do something about him.
He's always picking on me.
I know he is. I'm so sorry, honey. Hey.
- Hi. What's going on here?
-You'll see.
Kevin, get down here, please.
- Look what he did to my guitar.
- Aw. Again'!
God. You told Mom and Dad?
You have such a vagina.
Okay, enough, enough. Now, young man...
...we talked about the bullying
of your older brother.
That's right. We don't make fun of
someone just because they're different.
- I don't have a vagina.
-I'm just saying, if you did...
...it wouldn't be okay for Kevin
to tease you about your vagina.
Why are you making it sound
like I have a vagina?
I know you don't have a vagina.
I'm not doing that.
- Kevin, apologize to your brother, please.
-Fine. I'm sorry.
Now go to your room.
Ah. I was in my fucking room.
- Whoa, hey, Kevin? Get back down here.
-Ah.
Now listen.
There are a lot of boys who are born
with vaginas.
It's very hard for them.
- Honey. Why?
-it's a teachable moment, hon.
Gender fluidity, right?
It's a very serious issue.
- I'm not gender-fluid.
-it doesn't matter if you are.
The point is
your mom and I would love you...
...even if you were completely blank
down there.
Okay, this is not the point.
Kevin, just go to your room.
Hey, James, don't get your
gender fluid on me.
- Awesome.
- Stop. It's not a fluid.
And what about my guitar?
It's ruined.
Let me have a look.
There you go. That'll do for now.
Now get washed up. The Petersons
are coming over for dinner.
Okay, baby.
Oh, gosh. I'll get you a new guitar, okay?
- Oh, use the Vitamix. The dry bit.
-Just grind it. Yeah.
Sheila.
- So do you have to work tomorrow?
- So, um, Sheila.
- I want to go to the movies with my friends.
-Sheila.
- What?
-Do you like school this year?
It's okay.
"So do you like school this year?"
That's seriously
what you sound like. Just shut up.
God, I'm telling you, Russ,
you've gotta get one of these go-kart kits.
- What?
-Oh, yeah.
Gary and I spent the last two months
building this.
We took her out this morning
for the first time.
Hob; mob}.
- Fun?
-No, no, it was terrible. Oh, yeah, it was fun.
Hot damn, it's a go-kart.
G-man, get over here.
- G-man, G-man, G-man.
-Uh-oh.
Oh, my God, my G-man. I love him.
Get in there. What?
What? What?
Get in there. Get in there.
Oh, man. I love you so much.
Tell Mr. Griswold how dope our go-kart is.
It's got a Zanardi chassis and
a four-stroke Briggs and Stratton engine.
- Wow, and you guys built this together?
-We worked on it every day...
...after homework and toothbrushing.
I love-- Get over here, man.
Work it, Sugar Ray. Come on, Sugar Ray.
He's working me over.
I'm gonna eat your face!
Kevin, James, get over here.
No.
Come on, heh.
Oh, there you are.
- Dad, stop. What are you doing?
-Come on, man, we're sparring.
- We do this all the time.
-No. We never do this.
- Hey, don't hit your old man.
- I don't wanna be a part of this.
What are you doing?!
- This is how accidents happen.
Sacrifice!
Dad, let go of me. Stop.
Why did you do that?
I'm sorry, man. Come on.
I was just fooling around.
- That wasn't fun.
-Like we always do.
We never do that.
Hey, what do you say
you and I build a go-kart together?
If we have to.
Yeah, all right, G-man, heh!
Get out of here. Get out of here, G-man.
Did you just steal my son's nickname?
I'm not sure about-- Oh, shoot. Dang it.
Wow, your ring is getting loose,
there, Deb. Are you losing weight?
Yeah. I am. You know what I've been doing?
Spinning.
Yeah, it's a great stress reliever.
I'm gonna tell you what's
an even greater stress reliever.
And that is a week in Paris.
Oh, my gosh! I saw that on lnstagram.
All your pictures were so great.
- So you did see them.
-Yeah.
Funny, because I was gonna ask
how come you didn't like any of them.
What do you mean? I just said I did.
All my other friends, uh, who saw my
Paris pics, they clicked "like."
You were the only one who
didn't click "like."
Oh. I guess I just didn'! get around
to actually clicking "like" on them.
Okay, because look at this one.
Now, in this one we have...
...Sheila and Gary wearing berets.
-I know.
- Right?
-Heh. I like that one so much. It's so cute.
- But you didn't "like" it.
-Okay.
Here are the four of us
at the Arc de Triomphe.
Didn't "like" that. Didn't "like" my children.
Didn't "like" my man kissing on me.
I promise you the second you guys leave
I am gonna go upstairs online...
...and I am gonna click "like"
on every single one of them.
Honestly, honey, it really makes
no difference to me.
So are you guys going anywhere
special this summer'?
No. I wish. Yeah. No.
We are renting the same cabin that we've been
renting for 10 years in Cheboygan, Michigan.
The boys call it "Che-boring," Michigan.
- Isn't that funny?
- Why don't you just go someplace else?
No, we can't. Rusty loves it so much. I'd
break his heart if I told him we hate the cabin.
- Oh, boy. I understand.
-Yeah.
I understand.
Well, you know what the good news is?
Hmm?
Honestly, even if you go there and you
don't have a great time, baby...
...at least you know
that I will click "like" on all your photos.
Jesus Christ, Nancy.
Look!
Lug“!
What the fuck is this?!
Louie!
What the fuck is this?! Hey, madam.
How much capellini are you throwing away?!
What are you doing, Melinda?!
What are you doing?!
Guys, I have exciting news.
James has AIDS?
What? No. That's horrible.
- I'd be excited.
-Well, what is it? What is it?
- The four of us are gonna take a little trip.
- Paris.
Hmm. No, much better.
We're driving to Walley World.
- What?
- This family's in a rut.
We gotta shake things up, right'?
Spend a little quality time.
It wouldn't hurt for the boys
to learn to get along a little better.
- Uh, by locking them in a car together?
-Yeah.
- This is some bullshit right here!
-Hey, language.
Well, it is. I'm gonna miss the first
week of wrestling practice.
We'll find a wrestling range
along the way, heh.
That's not even a thing.
And, Dad, no offense,
I just don't wanna do my first big road trip...
...to some corporate theme park,
you know?
I'd like to explore the real America,
like Jack Kerouac or the Merry Pranksters.
- Don't say weird shit!
-Ah. Ow!
Kevin, bullying! Guys, come on.
My trip to Walla}; World when I was a kid
was the best time I ever had.
So you just wanna redo your vacation
from 3O years ago?
Don't you think that's gonna be
kind of a letdown?
No, no, no. We're not redoing anything.
This will be completely different.
For one thing, the original vacation
had a boy and a girl. This one has two boys.
And I'm sure that there will be lots
of other differences.
- I've never even heard of the original vacation.
-Doesn't matter.
The new vacation
will stand on its own, okay?
Come on, honey.
What do you say?
We can drive out and fly back.
Oh, what the heck, heh.
Couldn't be as bad as
that stupid cabin, right, honey?
- That's the spirit.
-All right.
Ugh. Fuck me.
Are we gonna drive all that way
in your little car?
Not exactly.
Come on, guys, heh. How come you didn't
follow me just then?
- Oh, you wanted us to?
-Yeah, that's why I dangled the key like that.
- Oh, well...
-Why else would l...?
You could've just said, "Come with me."
Look what your dad rented.
What the hell is that?
Kevin.
- That's a 2015 Tartan Prancer.
-Did you say "Tartan," honey'!
Yeah. Tanan's the Honda of Albania.
Why'd you get an Albanian car, Dad?
Renting a family car
on Memorial Day weekend...
...doesn't leave you with a lot of options.
But this baby is pretty sweet.
It's got all the latest Albanian technology.
Check it out. Plug-in hybrid.
Oh, wow, eco-friendly. Good.
So any time we run out ofjuice,
we can just pull right over, and plug in.
I don't know what that is.
Never seen an outlet for that, heh.
Should it retract, or...?
You would think
it would retract. It just...
No, it doesn't.
Cu pholder?
I think you coil it. You just coil it like that.
Right? Then you close it right up.
Doesn't matter. Still got two gas tanks.
- Why two?
- Carry twice as much gas.
- Why not just have one big tank?
-it's twice the gas, buddy.
Actually the same volume. Two small--
It has six ashtrays.
Six, wow.
Hope you guys like smoking.
- Right?
- Yeah.
What's with all the mirrors?
Safer.
But...
Oh. And this is amazing. I can control
the entire car from the fob.
- What do all the buttons mean?
- No clue. But we'll figure it out.
Honey, is that a swastika on there?
Yeah. We won't use that.
This is my favorite part.
- Slam the door on my arm.
-Heh. What?
It has a sensor. It won't let you
slam the door on your arm or leg.
- I'm not doing that.
-The rental guy showed me. Just do it.
- Okay.
-Do it!
- Do it.
-This is kind of fun.
Slam it.
All right. There you go.
- Oh! Oh!
'Oh, my God!
- Oh, my gosh!
-Goddamn it!
Oh, my God! Why did you have me do that?!
Oh, I didn't have the sensor activated.
- Okay.
-I'm an idiot.
- Do it again.
-No, absolutely not.
- It'll be fine. I just activated it.
-I won't do it.
- Don't be chicken.
-Fine.
- Shit!
-Heh.
- Why did you do that?
-Really?
You're right. I'm sorry, heh.
- Ugh! Nobody slam their arm in the door.
-Can I slam it on James' balls?
- You admit I have balls'?
-They hang out of your vagina.
- Stop that. Please.
-Plenty of time for that.
- Go get packed. We're hitting the road today.
-Okay.
Guess we're leaving today.
All right. Let's go, guys.
Huh.
Hey, honey. What's all that?
Well, uh, this is my dream journal...
...whimsy log...
...wish diary...
"m? Duems.
And, uh, this bad boy is going to be a
stream-of-consciousness travel log, so...
Yeah.
Come on, honey. Every boy that age
has a stack of diaries.
Okay, gang-
Seat belts on.
Two full tanks of gas.
Honey, GPS check?
Yes, yes. Roger that. Okay.
Your destination is 2560 miles ahead.
World, here we some.
Well, we're almost out of gas.
What? How is that possible?
We've been driving for less than an hour.
Dad, what's so special about Walla? World?
I mean, we have plenty of
theme parks at home.
Well, Walley World is home of
the one and only Velociraptor.
What the hell is that?
It's only the newest, scariest
roller coaster in the country.
Four hundred and fifty feet tall,
110 miles an hour...
...\riple corkscrew loop.
Yeah. Oh, hey, look at this.
Looks like we got ourselves
a little old convoy.
Let's say hi.
- Oh, my goodness. It has a CB radio in it?
-Yeah, comes standard in all Prancers.
- This way we can talk to truckers.
-Okay.
Now, guys, you just have
to speak their lingo.
I'm gonna ask him if there's any
police up ahead.
Breaker 1-9 to Rubber Ducky.
You got any Smokey the Bears
in your kitchen? Over.
You're clean and green
for the next 20 klicks.
- Ha-ha. He replied!
-I know!
- What did that even mean?
-I have no idea, but who cares?
- He seems nice.
-He does seem nice, doesn't he?
Copy that, good buddy. Over.
- Can ltry, Dad?
-Yeah, course.
When you finish talking, say "over."
- Okay. Cool.
-Okay.
Breaker 1-9, my friend Jessie says
all truck drivers are rapists.
- Are you a rapist?
-Kevin, no, no.
Sorry. Over.
- No, no, no.
-What are you doing?
- What? it's a question.
-Well, you're ruining it.
Sorry about that there, good buddy.
You know how little boys are
when their mouths get going, heh. I don't--
Not to imply that you are...
...fond of when little boys' mouths
get going in any way.
I am not suggesting that
you are a sex offender.
- Or a pedophile.
-Okay, no.
Yeah, so that's the CB radio, guys.
Neat, huh?
- Hey, Dad, what's a pedophile?
-Hmm. Well, Kevin, when a man and a boy...
...l0ve each other very much--
-No. No.
- I have to piss.
-Me too.
Go with him, please,
and keep an eye on him.
- Okay.
-Thank you.
- Look at that. The boys are bonding already.
-Mm-hm.
Isn't this the best?
Yeah.
Do you remember, back when you were
just getting your pilot's license...
...and you and I would sit there...
...and we'd talk about all those, like,
overseas trips we would take and stuff?
Yeah, of course that's when I thought
I was gonna fly for one of the big guys.
I know ifs not the most glamorous
airline, but Econo Air...
...it's been pretty good to us.
As far as I'm concerned, right here
with you and the boys, this is paradise.
- There was a hole in the side of my stall.
-You found a glory hole.
- Russ, no.
-All right, let's hit the road.
Go to sleep! Go to sleep!
- What's wrong with you?!
-I wanted to see...
...how long you could
hold your breath before you black out.
Don't do that. I could have died.
Whatever.
Goddamn it. Kevin!
Hey, honey, Why'd we get off the highway?
Thought it would be fun for the kids
to see where you went to college.
Oh, God. Why would that be fun
for them, honey?
You could give us a tour.
One of them could study there one day.
Oh, no. No way, man.
I've got my sights set on something
a little more Ivy League.
Oh. Little fucker.
- What, Ma?
-I love you. That's what I said.
- I love you too.
-I said, I love you.
Let's just see how far it is.
- You are 9.2 miles from destination.
- All right. Check the best route.
Oh, I changed the language.
That's not it, heh.
What is that?
- Uh, I don't know. Korean?
-Oh, God, it's horrible. Just please turn it off.
The menu's all in Korean now.
I don't know what to press.
Why is it so much angrier
than the other voices?
Why don't we just-I?
Honey, it doesn't like
when you touch it, okay?
Just leave it alone. Let it calm down.
Wow, this place has not changed a bit.
- Isn't that sorority row?
-Hmm.
Let's go check out your house.
Oh, no, honey. Don't you think we
should get back on the road?
No, come on. It'll be fun.
It's just a boring old house.
Yeah, that's what's up.
I cannot believe that they are still doing this.
What is it?
Uh, it is the Tri-Pi Chug Run.
You have to chug a big pitcher of beer...
...and then you have to get through
the course as fast as you can.
And you did this? Because you hardly drink.
No, yeah. But, honey, it's for charity, see?
Hi. Would you like to donate
to ass burgers?
Oh, no. We're just stopping by.
I was a Tri-Pi a long time ago, so...
In fact, the Chug Run was my idea.
-It was?
-Yeah.
- Wait, are you Debbie Fletcher?
Oh, my shit.
Oh, my shit! I can't believe it's you!
Guys, come here! Bring over the book!
- It's Debbie fucking Fletcher.
-How do you know who I am?
Oh, my God, are you kidding me?
You're like a legend at Tri-Pi.
- You're Debbie Do-Anything!
-Debbie Do-Anything?
- Go play.
- Yeah, look.
- See?
-Oh, God.
- Is it true you climbed the clock tower naked?
-Of course not.
Did you really show your tits
to anyone who asked?
- Honey, we should go.
-Hang on.
- I heard you stuck a finger in the dean's dick.
-Did you really burn down Taco Bell?
I heard you fucked Anthony Hopkins.
I heard that, if people bop you
on your head...
...gold coins come out of your butt.
- Okay, ladies, heh.
-What?
I think I know my wife pretty well, and she
wouldn't have done any of those things.
But you know what? What's important
is not whether I did them or I didn't do them.
What's important is that you guys are
idolizing very bad behavior here.
Uh, ew, you don't sound
like Debbie Do-Anything.
I had a feeling she was all hype.
Bet she didn't even come up
with the Chug Run.
Hey, wait a minute. Excuse me.
I did come up with the Chug Run, all right?
And I ran it.
- Sure you did.
- No, I did.
- In 16 seconds, okay?
-Okay, hon.
- Prove it.
-She can't do it now. She's old.
Excuse me, girl?
I didn't mean it like that.
I just mean...you're old.
Oh, yeah.
Never heard that laugh before. I don't like it.
Hold my bag. Uh-uh.
Why? You're not actually
going on this thing.
Yes, I am. This Chug Run raised
thousands of dollars for charity, all right?
I might not have gotten good grades
while I was here, but at least I did something.
It sounds like you did a lot.
You stuck your finger in the dean's penis.
It's not important what I stuck my finger in
and what I burnt down. What is important...
...is that these bitches are disrespecting me.
-"Bitches"?
Bring it on.
No one's calling me old. Fuck you.
All right, boobs, pitcher. Let's go.
Come on, come on, come on.
Tri-Pi, motherfuckers!
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Three! Two! One!
Oh, honey.
What's Mom doing?
She's, uh, teaching
these bitches a lesson.
This is the best thing I've ever seen.
Go! Go! Go!
Why is she puking so much?
It's for ass burgers.
Tri-Pi, motherfuckers.
Mom, you should try and stay hydrated.
What? What are you doing?
How about some tunes?
Oh, my God. I can't believe it.
I love this song.
Guys, it's Seal.
Heh. Everybody sing it with me.
There used to be a graying tower
Alone on the sea
Come on, guys.
You became
The light on the dark side of me
Deb?
Love remained
A drug that's the high and not--
Guys? No?
Did you know that when it snows
Kevin? James?
My eyes become large
Is this a man or a woman singing?
Ifs a man. And the coolest man ever.
He overcame lupus.
Baby
Icompare you to a kiss from a rose on the gray
I can't believe
no one in this family wants to sing.
--stranger it feels, yeah.
Batman Forever?
--that your rose is in bloom
Val Kilmer.
A light hits the gloom on the gray
He's come back to kill us.
- Gun it, Russ!
-Gunning it.
You gotta go faster, Dad!
Go faster!
- The Prancer doesn't go any faster!
- What do we do?!
Maybe if I press this rabbit button...
- ...it'll give it a boost or something.
- Yes, try it.
- Why is there a button for that?
-And why is it a rabbit?
Okay»-
- Uh, rocket. Here you go. Try that.
- Yes.
What? What's happening?
- Why am I swiveling?
-I don't know!
- Grab the wheel!
-it won't slop!
- Hit the gas! Hit the gas!
-Okay, I'm trying to hit--
We're gonna die!
- Okay, I got the wheel. I got the wheel.
-Okay, okay.
Okay, what are we gonna do?
- I have an idea.
-What'?
- Handbrake turn.
-What?
Pull the wheel left, yank the handbrake,
do a 180, cross the median, drive past him.
- You know how, Dad?
-If Vin Diesel can do it, so can I.
- Why are you as good as Vin Diesel?
- Hang on.
That's not what I was trying to do.
- Everybody okay?
-Oh, shit!
- Go, Dad! Go, go!
-Oh, my God.
- Oh, shit!
-Goddamn it.
All right, boys. This is you.
- I call both beds.
- You get one bed.
If you need anything, Mom and I
are next door.
Oh, uh, I think I saw a hot tub, Dad.
Is it okay if I take a soak?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
But if anyone tries to
shove you in their car...
...give them a good scratch
like I showed you.
- I will.
-All right.
- Attaboy.
-Thanks.
So...
...how come you never told me about
the whole Debbie Do-Anything thing?
Heh. Come on, that was so long ago.
Yeah, but it's part of who you are...
...and I wanna know all about you.
All right. Well, that's fair.
What do you wanna know?
How many guys did you sleep with
before me?
No, no, no.
- No, no, no.
-Oh, come on.
Come on. That's not important.
- No, I know. But I'm just--
-You really need to know'?
- It just...
-Oh, okay.
- I'm just curious.
-Okay, okay.
Um, let's see.
And then...
Kind of taking you a little while, heh.
Okay, uh, so around...
- Three.
Three. That's actually reassuring,
because, heh, ifs the same as me.
No, didn't say three.
Thirteen? Thirteen?
- Nope.
-And it's not three?
Ifs around 30.
Thirty! Phew.
Wow, holy cow.
See, now I feel like you're judging me.
I'm judging me-.
- Your number is so much higherthan mine.
-Yes, it is a big number...
...bul it doesn't matter.
Honey, it doesn't matter.
You're so cool. I feel like a loser.
You are not a loser, okay?
Yeah? Because, uh, I had to work pretty hard
just to get those three.
Had to take care of Jenny's grandfather
for months before she slept with me.
- And he was racist.
-Please, don't base it on me.
I was, like, crazy back then.
I was completely immature and acting out...
...and just really, like, free with my body...
...and that's just not who I am anymore.
That's not who we are.
Well, we're pretty free with our bodies.
But you have to admit...
...I feel like we've gotten...
...like, less free with our bodies.
But we have sex every week
with our bodies.
We do. But...
I mean, ifs gotten a little routine, babe.
You know, you always are lighting
that same Yankee Candle and everything.
And I don't know, it might be nice to
mix it up a little bit every once in a while.
Okay? No big deal.
I'm gonna go take a shower, okay?
I'm gonna take one with you.
- Hmm?
-Uh... We'll have sex in it.
Yeah. In the shower.
How's that for getting free
with our bodies, Debbie Do-Anything?
- I like that.
-Yeah.
Oh, Russ.
Just be careful not to drop the soap.
Oh, I won't.
What?
- This is fun and different.
-I know. It is.
You are so cute when you get
excited about stuff.
You're, like, so cute always.
Aw, honey.
Oh, my-- Holy shit! Are those mushrooms?!
Looks like somebody...
...blew their head off in there.
-Oh, God.
So should we, uh...?
Should we get in or...?
No, right, heh?
Yeah. I'm gonna see if there's
something to clean that with.
Hmm. Maybe the housekeeping left a...
Oh, well, here's a Brillo Pad.
I'll just--
- Russ.
- Yeah.
That's not a Brillo Pad.
It's a ball of pubic hair.
- Oh, my gosh.
-There's so much of it.
Who has that much pubic hair?
It's not even possible.
No, not one person.
That's all different colors.
That's from like 30 different guys.
Oh, shut up, Russ.
No. I'm sorry.
Through the curtains hanging in the window
In the evening on a Friday night
Little light shining through the window
Lets me know everythingls gonna be all right
Summer breeze makes me fee! fine
Blowing through the jasmine in my mi--
You're pretty good.
Jeez, sorry.
I, uh, heh, didn't mean to scare you.
- Hi.
- You were in the Jeep.
-And you were in that plastic bag.
That was my stupid brother.
Gotcha. Big brothers suck.
Oh, no.
Yeah, big, heh.
I'm Adena.
James.
- I have a penis.
-What?
It's on your guitar.
- Same brother.
-What an asshole.
Yeah.
You wanna go in?
Absolutely.
Well, what have we here?
Little Romeo and Juliet situation?
My name's Russ. Pleased to meet you both.
I'm just a stranger, passing through town.
But I couldn't help noticing how
incredibly handsome this young man is.
What's your story? You got a girlfriend?
No.
What? No girlfriend?
Cute boy like that?
Somebody's gonna snatch you up.
- Do you want me to call the cops?
-No.
And he plays guitar?
Dream boy.
- Make a muscle.
-I'd...
- Do it.
- ...rather not.
Take your shirt off. Make a muscle.
- I really don't want to.
-Don't be shy.
- Show us what you're working with.
-All right.
Um, I should go.
Are you sure that you'll be okay?
I think so.
0K8)'-
Bye.
Dang it.
- Dad, why would you do that?
-Saw you talking to her.
- Figured you could use a wingman.
-I didn't need a wingman.
- Well, heh, looks like you did. She left.
-That's because you were approaching--
You know, James, when I was your age...
...Grandpa Clark sat me down
and we had a little chat.
Seeing you with that girl made me
realize that we haven't had that chat yet.
- We don't need that chat.
-Yeah?
Come on, I know it's embarrassing,
but it'd be a lot more embarrassing...
...if you found yourself tummy to tummy
with a lady friend...
...and didn't know what goes where.
-I know what goes where.
- You do?
-Uh-huh.
- You sure?
-Yep.
All right, all right.
Well, I just want you to know...
...I'm here to answer any questions
you might have about that stuff.
No matter how uncomfortable it seems.
Yeah, okay.
- Yeah, right. Here it comes.
-Yeah. All right. Okay.
Uh, there were some kids at school
who were talking about...
...rim jobs.
- Hmm.
- So, whats that? What's a rim job?
- Rim jobs.
-Yeah.
- Is that R-I-M?
-Mm-hm.
Rim job. Country of origin.
I don't know. Urn, America.
Can I hear it in a sentence?
- What's a rim job, Dad?
-Oh.
Well, rim job.
I would guess a rim job is when you
kiss someone with your mouth closed.
Right? So you're only using
the rim of your mouth.
- That's it?
-Sure.
It felt like it was something way dirtier.
No, I mean, what else could it be?
Any other questions?
I guess not.
Good talk, James.
Now, I hope you're not too old
to let your dad give you...
...a good-night rim job.
Looks like we might get to
Aunt Audrey's before dinner.
Will Uncle Stone be there?
Yeah, I suppose he will.
- Uncle Stone is cool.
-You have to be cool to be a celebrity.
Heh. He's not exactly a celebrity.
I mean, he's a local weatherman. That's all.
Uh, actually, Audrey said that
the networks are interested in him.
- Yeah?
-Oh, yeah.
All right. Well, good for him.
- Think Uncle Stone will let me ride his horse?
-I don't see why not.
- Do you think I can shoot his guns?
-No, you cannot.
Too bad. I would've shot you
right off that fucking horse.
I never would've imagined my sister
marrying such a conservative.
Yeah, but just because Stone's
political beliefs are different than ours...
...doesn't mean he's not good-looking. I--
A good person.
- You said it.
-Uh, honey--
Hey, look at that!
Hot springs up ahead.
We've always wanted to do that.
Oh, honey,
we don't wanna be late to Audrey's.
So we're a few minutes late.
We're on vacation. Right? Come on.
Let's have some fun.
0K8)'-
- Oh. Look at the line.
-This will take forever.
Come on, guys. How often do we get
to soak in hot water?
Every time we take a bath.
No, this is different, okay? This is natural.
This water was heated
in Mother Nature's bowels.
Oh. Gross.
There's gotta be another way in.
I'm gonna ask this gentleman.
I bet he'd know.
Excuse me, sir.
- Hi there.
-Hey. Hi.
Hey, we were wondering. Is there
another entrance to the hot springs?
Like a secret entrance the locals use?
- Line can get pretty long this time of year, huh?
-Yeah. Yeah, it sure can.
Yeah, I'll tell you what you'll do.
Uh, can you see that dirt road?
That path there on the left?
- Yeah.
-If you just follow that all the way up...
...that'll take you to the hot springs.
All right, perfect. Thank you.
Oh, no, no. You bet. Y'all have a good time.
- Oh, will do, heh.
- Heh.
Hey, what's your pet rat's name?
Is my pet what?
What the fuck? What the fuck?!
What the fuck?!
I don't know him.
Honey, are you sure about this?
I mean, nobody else is going this way.
Yeah, well, most people think
inside the box.
But you know who thinks outside the box?
Uncle Stone?
Me. Your father.
Um, honey, I don't see any hot springs.
Well, the guy said it was
right at the end of this road, so...
Well, the guy also did not know he had
a rat on his shoulder, so there's that.
Hold on.
Wow, honey, this is beautiful.
- Isn't it?
-Yeah.
All right, everyone.
In your bathing suits. Now! Heh.
Looks like we found our
own private hot spring.
- I say we call it "Griswold Springs."
-Heh.
- The water's perfect.
-Oh, my God. It's so nice.
Why does it smell like rotten eggs?
- That's the sulfur, buddy. It's natural.
-Yeah.
Yeah. And ifs really good for you too.
Actually, the minerals that are
in this mud here...
...they draw toxins out of your body.
Can you believe that?
Cool, right?
Oh, wow.
Mm. This is perfect.
It's exactly what we needed.
Oh, yeah. Good call, Griswold.
- Oh, man.
-Yeah.
- Oh, yeah. That's it.
-That's it. That's it.
I can feel my body detoxifying.
You know...
...it tastes a little shitty, but I think
that's part of it. That's okay.
This is wonderful.
That is the stuff.
What is that, honey?
On your ear. What's on your ear?
What is that?
It's an ear!
Look, James. Found a dart.
Are you crazy?
Oh, my God!
Everybody out of Griswold Springs!
- Get out of the poop!
- That was nasty!
All over me!
I don't like Griswold Springs.
Is that our car alarm?
What?
Ugh. How come that local guy didn't tell us
there are thieves in these woods?
Oh, right.
He took my guitar.
Oh, my God. He took all our money, Russ.
All right, not a best-case scenario.
But, hey.
He left your book.
So, I guess we get the last laugh.
Oh, really, honey?
We're naked and covered in human waste.
Oh, come on, sweetheart.
We don't know that it's human.
This is so embarrassing.
I feel like your cousin Eddie's family.
It's no big deal. We'll just tell
Stone and Audrey what happened.
Kids, remember what happened?
We pulled over to rescue a baby
from a burning car...
...and somebody stole all of our stuff
while we were distracted.
And why are we naked
and covered in feces?
I don't remember.
That's right. We don't remember.
Oh, my God.
Oh, come on.
- What're we gonna do?
-Can you give me a hand with this? Please?
Just-- Yeah.
Oh, gosh.
- I can't. I can't get it off.
-Just use your spit.
Oh, okay.
Focus on the balls.
If you guys wanna stop, that's! be good too.
Stay on the balls. I've got the shaft.
Hi, y'all!
Hey. Oh, my goodness. Hi.
What happened?
Well, that's a--
it's a crazy story--
Dad got scammed by a guy at a park.
- Kevin.
-Same old Rusty.
You'd buy water from a faucet.
Anyway, you guys look disgusting.
I have some clothes
I was gonna give to the church...
...if you guys wanna borrow some of those.
- Great. Thank you, Audrey.
-Yeah.
- Come on inside.
-All right.
Boy, y'all stink.
Oh, I don't like that.
Man, this place makes our house
look like shit.
Well, Kevin, that's only because a dollar goes
much further out here than it does in Chicago.
Especially when you make a
lot more of them, heh.
Just messing with you.
Shoot, you boys are growing faster
than a weed under a faucet.
- You still rassling, son?
-Uh-huh.
Uh-huh. Oh, come on.
Show me what you got.
- Hey, Kevin. Get off your brother, please.
-They'rejust having themselves a rassle.
- It's what brothers do.
- Hey, oh, look at you guys.
Hot damn. Debbie Griswold.
You just keep getting prettier.
- Oh, stop.
- No, I mean it.
You could make hot water
come out of the cold faucet.
Oh, heh. That's very sweet.
You know, I remember the night
you first wore that dress.
- You remember that night?
-I remember that night.
- I'll never forget that night.
- Neither will I, baby.
You're my fucking husband.
Oh, betcha, I am. I'm yourcaveman.
I'll rip you in half.
I wanna have all your babies.
Oh, baby.
I hit the fucking jackpot with you.
Oh, God, what I'm gonna do
to you tonight.
Who wants to see Stone's man cave?
Yeah.
Is this Charlton Heston?
Yep, Chuck was a good friend.
I can't tell you how many nights
we spent drinking bourbon together...
...crying about the state of this country.
It's true, they did.
They literally cried together.
Hmm. Somehow I don't see you
crying, though, Stone.
Yeah, that's, uh...
That's kind of embarrassing, right?
Not embarrassing to me.
Even the strongest faucet
sometimes lets out a few drops, heh.
What is with these faucets?
Everyone thought that F-4 twister...
- ...was gonna bypass Harris County.
- Not my Stone.
I had a feeling that that low-pressure system
was gonna make a beeline for Mission Bend.
Thanks to my report, those people had
an extra 15 minutes to evacuate.
- Ah.
-Governor Perry said he saved 2000 lives.
That's how many we lost at Pearl Harbor...
...s0 basically he stopped Pearl Harbor.
That's when the national news called.
Now, between us...
...it's looking good. Ain't it, honey?
Course none of that would've been
possible without my sugar mama here...
...working day and night to put me
through meteorology school.
I liked working, baby.
I didn't mind it one bit.
Well, you never have to do it again, darling.
But it kind of gave me purpose.
Nope, never again. That is a promise.
Wow, Uncle Stone, I may not agree
with your politics...
- ...but that doesn't mean I don't admire you.
- Well, thank you.
But the man you should admire the most
is sitting right next to you.
But there's nobody there.
Oh, I don't mean that chair.
I mean your pa right here.
Okay, heh.
- He doesn't save anybody's life.
- Doesn't he?
Well, every time he flies that little plane
of his, he's saving lives by not crashing.
And in my book...
...that makes him a hero.
Thank you.
You know, a lot of people actually--
Not to mention, he also snagged himself
one sweet slice of foxy pie in your mama there.
You gotta stop that today. Stop it.
You know what I always wanted
to know was...
...when did you first know the weather?
You all right, Deb?
- What?
-Hey, there's a cow.
Oh, not a cow. That's a steer.
That there is $6000 worth ofjuicy,
purebred Angus beef.
It's Stone's new passion, raising cattle.
He's even named them.
Uh-huh.
Old Sebastian here loves him some ribs.
Here you g0, b0)'-
Yeah. Oh, that's it.
- Dad, isn't that“?
-Cannibalism? Yeah.
You boys get up early tomorrow, you can
watch me herd these suckers into the corral.
- Oh!
-Wai! a minute, wait a minute.
You herd them yourself?
Heh, I'm a man, aren't I?
Yes.
Uh, hey, Stone, not sure if you need
a hand out there, but I'd love to help.
Sure thing. If you're up for it
I can always use an extra set of hands.
Well, I was born with an extra set of hands.
That's an odd thing to say, heh.
But I reckon this'll be
the highlight of your trip.
Well, the real highlight, of course,
will be when we get to Walla}; World...
...and I take my family on the Velociraptor.
I think it is so weird. I don't know
why you want to go back to Walley World...
...after Dad flipped out there.
Audrey, Dad flipped out because
he loved us and wanted us to be close.
And we were.
And that's all I want for my family.
You're such a clown.
You're a clown.
Babe, baby, I think Rusty's right.
You know, family is the most
important thing there is.
Little something...
Maybe we'll take baby Cooper
on a trip this summer.
Yeah, not to Walla? World.
- Oh, God, no.
-Because thafd be stupid.
That'd be stupid.
How about Paris?
And then we get back
I can maybe get a part-time job?
Well, not while there's breath
in my body, sweetheart.
You know, honey, I am really happy
for your sister.
- Yeah?
-Seriously.
She and Stone seem really in love. It's nice.
These pants Stone gave me are really
stretched out in the crotch.
Weird. Why would they be
stretched out in the-f?
- God, I don't know.
-Holy shit.
How much you think they paid
for this house?
Whoa. Oh, okay, whoa.
Oh, should I see if Audrey has
a Yankee Candle?
Fuck the Yankee Candle.
I wanna do this now.
- Oh, God, you're so sexy. Oh, my God.
-Oh, what has gotten into you?
What'! What, what?
This is because of him, isn't it?
What? Who?
Because of who?
Because of Stone.
- What?
-That's why you're jumping my bones.
- You're thinking of him.
-That's ridiculous.
Then how come the one night
we're with him...
...you turn into some kind of sexual character?
-I don't know where you're going with this--
- Where's your wedding ring?
-Oh, my God.
Before we got here, you took off
your wedding ring?
No, I didn't, Rusty. It was loose.
You remember how loose it was?
And I musfve just dropped it somewhere.
What was the plan? Show up
with no ring, he'll think you're single?
How will he think I'm single
if I'm here with my husband?
I don't know. It was your plan.
It was not my pl-- Okay.
Yes, Stone is an impressive man, okay?
But I married you, Rusty.
And I am so sorry that I lost my ring...
...but I would never, ever, ever
take it off on purpose.
I know, I know. I just...
I freaked out. I'm sorry. I just...
We'll get you another ring.
I liked that one.
Hey, y'all decent?
- Yes. Hi.
-Hey.
Okay. Just wanted to make sure y'all
had everything you needed for the night.
Yep.
All right.
Man, it sure is beautiful here
this time of year, ain't it?
And quiet. Listen.
You hear that?
- No.
-Exactly. It's perfect silence.
Hmm.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, uh, TV remote.
Okay, let me show you.
I've got, uh, channels...
...and the volume.
On. Off.
- Pretty straightforward.
-Yeah.
- Yeah.
-Great.
All right.
Well, uh, if you get thirsty,
there's fresh milk in the fridge...
...and have yourselves a good night.
Uh-huh.
- Okay.
- Night, Stone.
-Good night, Stone.
Man.
Yeah.
0K8)'-
He totally just came in here
to show off his six-pack.
Hey, morning.
Ugh, barely.
How come you gotta do this at 6 a.m.?
Well, I gotta be at the station by 7:30".
...for Stone Crandall's AccuWeather Report.
Hey, you ever ride one of these things?
No, never have.
But, uh, can't imagine it's more
complicated than an Airbus A318.
Heh, yeah, well, that's the spirit.
Now, the key here is to move
back and forth along the edge of the herd.
You keep your distance, though.
You don't want to spook them.
Got it.
0K8)'-
Are there helmets?
Yeah, I keep them with the tampons.
Just basic safety.
This is exciting!
It's my favorite way to start the day.
This, and making love to your sister.
Thank you for that.
Come on, let's go!
It looks like we got us
a couple of mavericks.
You take the one on the left.
I'll take the one on the right.
Unless you need my help with yours.
No, I think I got it.
Last one to the corral's
a rotten cowpoke.
Let's go!
Go! Get up! Get up! Get up! Let's go!
Whoa!
Hey!
Holy shit!
Oh, my gosh'.!
ls the cow okay?
No, the cow's not okay, Russ.
You drove plumb through him.
Oh, no, Sebastian.
Gross.
Hey. sang, uh...
Maybe for lunch we could find
a burger place.
You know, like a, uh...
Like a drive-through burger place.
I don't know, Dad. I think we should, uh...
...steer clear of that.
- Good one, James.
-All right, enough, you guys.
Dad hit a cow, okay? Let's just move on.
- Oh, I got one.
-Yeah? Let's hear it.
James is a piece of shit.
You kind of missed the point there, buddy.
- Hey, hey.
-What'! What is it? What's wrong?
- Is everything okay?
-Yeah.
- No, nothing's wrong.
-Okay.
- Well, what?
-I have an idea.
And it's gonna sound crazy,
but hear me out, okay?
.Ok8Y-
.Okay-
We're right near
the Four Corners Monument...
...which is where four states
come together in one spot.
- So?
-Let's go have sex on it.
What? Heh.
Yeah, that way we can make love in
four states at the same time.
Wait.
You're serious?
Yeah. I mean, you're the one who
said we should mix it up.
What's more mixed-up than sex
on a public monument?
Um, pretty sure Debbie Do-Anything
would do it.
Okay, well, Debbie Do-Anything
was a dumb-ass.
Maybe that's what we need.
To be dumbasses together.
What about the kids?
Well, Kevin's kind of a dumb-ass.
No, no, honey.
What are we gonna do about them?
They're fine. They're fast asleep.
We'll be back
before they know we're gone.
- Okay.
-Yeah?
All right, let's do it.
Mom?
Dad?
- James?
-Mom?
- Adena?
-Are you, like, stalking me or something?
No. What? No.
I'm kidding.
- Relax ,heh.
-Oh!
Hey, what happened with that perv
who was hitting on you in Arkansas?
That was actually my dad.
He was trying to be my wingman.
Oh, my God.
He's a really shitty wingman.
So no guitar tonight?
It got stolen.
That sucks.
I really liked hearing you play.
You did?
Yeah, I've always had a thing for musicians.
Well, good...
...because I've always had a thing for...
...pretty girls.
Well played.
See? You don't need a wingman.
Here it is.
Oh, my God. This is so illegal.
- I know, it's so hot, right?
-Yeah.
I am hard as a faucet right now.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
-Oh. No. I like it.
- Yeah?
-Yeah.
-I do.
- You like it when I slap that ass?
-I do, I do, heh.
- Good. I'm gonna beat the shit out of your ass.
-Whoa, Russ.
Okay, right here?
- We're about to have sex outside.
-I know. Heh, I know.
- Do you want me to put a finger in?
-In what?
- Never mind.
-Okay, okay.
Y'all wanna keep it down?
- Yeah! Yeah!
-Hey, watch it, man!
- Get your leg off me!
-You're so slippery and sweaty!
If you're here to have sex on the Corners,
we're next. Get in line.
- Oh, my gosh.
-Oh, God.
Oh, God!
Oh, God! They're in every state!
So many boobies out here!
You two! Freeze!
Go, go, go!
Hands up!
- Run! Honey, run!
- Get your shoe!
Drop the flashlight!
You do know public indecency
is a crime in the state of Utah?
Yes. Sorry, officer.
- See, we're married, and we wanted to just--
-Save it for the judge.
It makes me sick how you deviants show up
and desecrate this holy place every night.
- Turn around. Hands behind your back.
-What?
Not so fast, Tommy.
Shoot for sherbet.
What are you doing here, Kyle?
These people are clearly in the state
of Colorado. That's my jurisdiction.
Juris-dick in my ass, Kyle.
Look at her left foot. Smack-dab in Arizona.
You weed-legalizing, Mile-High piece of shit.
- Hey, there's no reason for that language.
-Sorry, Officer Mormon.
You don't like that? I have an idea.
Why don't you plug up your ears
with Mitt Romney's dick?
- Ha, ha.
-Hey.
Oh, looks like New Mexico decided
to wake up from his siesta.
- What's the trouble?
-Tell you what the trouble is, dreamcatcher.
You are wearing entirely too much
goddamn turquoise.
Hey, we can do this without...
...disrespecting each other's traditions.
-Oh, go fuck your wives, Tommy.
This is what I'm telling you.
Every night we do this.
You know what this border represents?
It's just an idea. That's all I'm saying.
- If it's just an idea, then I'll just get the perp--
-Ah! My house!
- Hey!
-Stay out of my state.
- What are you gonna do now?
-Get your feet off of my state!
You wanna stomp on my foot?!
- You back--
-Is that what you want?
Hey, I wasn't even in it!
Don't you kick in here! Don't start...
How about this, then, huh'?
- We got a live weapon!
-Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
- Think I'm afraid of that?
-I'm not afraid of you.
- How about that, huh?
-Oh, yeah, like I'm afraid?
- Are we--? I don't want it in my mouth.
-Let's not do that.
- I'll take that all in, dude.
-That's enough! Everyone get down!
- Get down on the ground! Get down!
-Get down! Get down on the ground!
I'm cooperating!
I'm the one who's cooperating!
- You get down too. You get down too.
-Get down on the ground!
- Hands where?
-Your right side.
- Sides or front?
-Side to side.
- Let's do this.
-Everyone down'?
- Okay.
-I think I'm done.
You can really see all the stars out here.
Yeah.
So, what do you feel like doing?
Heh. I don't know.
Can I give you a rim job'?
- Whoa.
-No.
- What?
-I don't know.
- What's wrong with you?
-I don't know. I'm sorry.
What did you wanna do?
I don't know. I thought maybe we could...
...kiss or something?
Well, yeah, that's what I thought l...
Yeah. Okay.
Ow.
Where's Mom and Dad, dork?
I don't know.
Just go back inside the thing.
You were about to let that dingus kiss you?
Shut up, Kevin.
- Who is that?
-My stupid little brother.
I thought you said he was your big brother.
-L-- Damn it!
-Dingus.
- Why do you take that from him?
-Am I supposed to hit him back?
- He's a little kid.
-He's a little shit.
- You don't have to let him push you around.
-I kind of thought I was taking the high road.
Yeah, that seems to be working out for you.
You know what?
Fuck it.
Okay, so you wanna do this now?
Bring it, bitch.
Wait, what?
No, no, no.
Wow, this is so easy.
You are such a little boy.
Unh! There's gonna be a few changes,
all right? No more bullying.
- Stop it. I'm telling Mom.
-Shut your mouth.
You gonna stop bullying?
You're hurting my tummy.
Say you're gonna stop, you little piece of...
...ass.
-Wait, what?
-"Piece of ass"?
-You know what I mean.
What are you doing to my face?
- This hurts, doesn't it?
-Dude.
- How do you like your ears getting messed up?
-it's really not that bad.
- I'll tap you on the forehead.
- That's not how you beat someone up.
Very dehumanizing.
Your forehead's gonna be so sore.
Stop it! What are you doing?!
- How do you like your lips getting tickled?
-This is really weird.
Just smush your cheeks.
- You gonna stop bullying?
-Fine, I'll stop bullying. Just stop doing this.
Thank you, Adena.
This has been...
...the best night of my life.
Weird fucking family.
Well, that was awful.
At least the kids never woke up.
Passengers on the left side
of the Prancer will notice...
...the Grand Canyon out the window.
That's right. Last stop before Walla? World.
So, guys...
...when we visited the Grand Canyon
when I was a kid...
...we barely had a chance to look at it.
This time...
...we're gonna do a whole lot more
than look.
- Oh, cool.
- Sweet.
Hi, folks! Hi!
All right, let's see, who do we got here?
You must be...
...the Fung family.
Huh?
I'm just messing!
You're the Griswolds, right?
Yes, that's right.
Heh, right. The little guy's face
was like, "Fungs?"
Anyway, I'm Chad. I'm gonna be your guide.
- Okay. Hi, Chad.
-You couldn't have come on a better day.
I'll get you all geared up.
And, guess what, the river's
running way high...
...so I think we're in for
a pretty sweet ride, guys.
- Let's roll.
-All right.
Let's do this.
Okay, gang, joke time is over.
Let's get serious for a second.
Go over a couple safety procedures
before we hit the water.
First off, do any of you know this river?
Because this is actually my first time.
I'm kidding, ha, ha.
Been doing this about three and a half years.
Know the river inside and out.
Got my guide certificate from
a Cracker Jack box.
Guys, it's a joke.
See the little kid's face? He's all:
"A Cracker Jack box? A what?!"
All you gotta do is follow my instructions...
...and we got a 50-50 chance
of coming back alive.
I'm kidding, guys.
See the little kid's face, he's all:
"I'm coming back alive! I don't wanna die!"
Sorry, hang on a second.
I'm getting a call from my fiancée here.
Just got engaged two weeks ago.
so I think I'm gonna take this...
...or the river's not gonna be the only
hot water I'm in today.
River's actually very cold.
Hey, boo.
- Wow, this is awesome.
-Ah.
We're about to set sail through one of
America's greatest aquatic treasures.
- Kevin, don't hit your brother.
-I didn't.
You heard what he said
about the "aquatic treasures," right?
- Yeah.
-And you didn't wanna hit him'?
- Well, that's progress.
-Wow.
I don't understand, though.
Like, what are you even saying?
But just like that?
I love you. You love me.
Tanya, please. Please, just let's
think about this for a second, honey.
You're all that I have in this world.
Tanya, no, babe.
No, Tanya, no. Please, don't hang up.
No, no! Goddamn it!
Who's ready to go on the river?
Um, are you okay, Chad?
Oh, yeah.
Turns out I'm not engaged anymore.
30...
All aboard.
I don't know about this, Russ.
Oh, come on.
He's kidding.
Get it together!
Oh, shit.
Everybody out of the boat.
Can we go home now?
What?
We're a day away from Walla? World.
Dad, I don't think any of us
really care about Walley World.
The boys are right, Russ. I mean,
we almost died back there.
I mean, isn't it time that we just
cut our losses?
I cannot believe what I'm hearing.
Oh, my God.
Huh! All right, that has to be a sign, right?
We were meant to finish this trip.
Come on, guys, everybody sing it with me.
There used to be a graying tower
Alone on the sea
We're losing the station.
- We're not losing anything.
- Yes--
We just have to listen a little harder!
Love remained
A drug--
Okay, no, no, no. It's gone. It's gone.
- Just let it go.
- Fine.
Just thought we could all sing Seal
together like normal families do.
- Oh, crap.
- Now what?
- We're almost out of gas.
-Oh, my God.
It's all right.
I'm sure we will find a place to fill up
around here before we run out.
Man.
No signal at all.
Wonder if the Prancer has
roadside assistance.
- How would we even call them?
-Maybe it's one of the buttons on the fob.
Seriously? You're gonna keep
pressing buttons?
- Well, we never tried the top hat.
-Oh, jeez.
Oh, my God!
Well, now we know what the top hat does.
I'm not gonna do the swastika.
All that's left is the muffin.
Come on, muffin.
- What?
- It started.
- Yes.
-All right.
Oh, must be the extra gas tank.
- Right?
-The muffin.
Dad to the rescue.
Thank God. Wait, where's it going?
Wait! Wait a minute!
- Make it stop!
-I don't know how!
I'll hit the muffin again!
- All right, we can handle this.
-Oh, no, no, no. Please, don't say that.
Do not say that we
can handle this, Russ. Okay?
- We can.
- No, we can't!
We can't!
From the moment we left for this trip,
nothing has gone right.
Can you please just admit that
this was a mistake?
But it wasn't. Right? We all wanted to go.
- I didn't.
-Me neither.
Me neither.
You wanted to go.
All right, I think tempers are getting
a little hot right now. We just have to, uh...
We just all have to...
Fuck me!
I give up!
All I wanted to do was take
my fucking family...
...on a fucking trip to Walley World,
and ride the fucking Velociraptor!
Ow. There's a rock in that.
I guess I'm the asshole for trying to
bring my family closer together.
What do I get? Kids who don't wanna be
with me, and a wife who's miserable.
- Russ...
- Oh, come on, Debbie.
You know it's true. You think you settled
for me. You think I'm a loser regional pilot.
Well, guess what.
I get offers from international
carriers all the time...
...and I turn them down. Why?
I don't wanna be away from you
and the kids that long.
I'm an idiot.
I should take one of those jobs
and fly off to the Pyramids of Zambezi...
...and the Lost Gardens of...
...wherever the fuck!
Just forget it.
Forget this whole stupid trip.
You people are on your own.
I'm sure you'll find a better
husband and father.
A cowboy with a huge six-pack...
...who will take you to Paris...
...and wrestling...
...and books.
What--?
Wait, where are you going?
Fuck if I know!
Ow. God!
These tumbleweeds are all filled
with things that are hard!
What the...?
Oh, no.
Help.
Help!
Stop!
Come on. Go, go, go.
Help!
No!
- Don't you kill him!
-Dad!
I'm so sorry.
When I called you a pedophile, I was--
No! No, no, no!
No! Not in front of my family!
Your wife left this in a truck stop in Missouri.
Thought you might want it back.
Oh, my God.
Wait, wait.
Is that my ring?
This man's been trying to return it
to us the whole time.
I don't know how I could ever thank you.
No thanks necessary.
It was on my way.
So you're not a rapist?
Looks like your car's pretty messed up.
Where you headed?
Um...
Home, I guess.
Well, I can take you as far as
San Francisco. Will that help?
Yeah. Yeah, that'll work.
Thank you.
All right, come on, guys.
- He still didn't answer me.
- Oh, Kevin.
Well, thanks for the ride.
Really appreciate it.
You never told us why you keep
that teddy bear on the front of your truck.
- Oh, yeah.
-it makes the kids feel more comfoflable.
Oh, yeah? You have kids?
Nope.
Right. Take care.
Well, I guess that's that.
Yeah. We'll get a flight home tomorrow.
Do not stay here.
Worst bed and breakfast we've been to.
They ought to shut this place down.
The owner is a lunatic.
You all come back now, you hear?
Hey, look who made it.
Ellen! Oh, there you are. They're here.
Hi, Dad.
- We were so happy to get that call.
- Hi.
How was your trip?
- It's a long story.
- Give me a hug.
- Hi, Grandpa.
-Oh. Come here, you two.
Oh, my gosh. You're getting so big.
- Come on, let's go inside.
-Grandpa, you don't have to.
- No, I can do it. Really.
-Russ.
- Clark.
- Oh, no. I got this.
I'm fine.
This really hurts.
Then the muffin made the car explode,
but it didn't matter.
Our luggage and all of our stuff
was already stolen...
...by the guy with the rat on his shoulder.
-Even took my guitar.
Oh, James, that's terrible.
A musician without his instrument is
as bad as...
...a shoemaker without a toilet seat.
Ah, I may have something for you.
It's very fragile. Look.
- You take care of that.
-Wow, Grandpa.
Thank you so much.
- Cool.
-Yeah.
Doesn't look like much,
but that's a very special guitar.
- It was given to me by Bob Dillon.
-The Bob Dylan?
No, a Bob Dillon.
D-I-L-L-O-N.
- An accountant friend of mine.
-Oh.
But it was given to him by Jimmy Hendricks.
- The Jimi Hendrix?
-No.
So how's the B-and-B business going?
Oh, we love it, are you kidding?
It's a great fit for us. We love visitors.
We love having people around
to care for. We're people people.
- Hey, guys. You mind if we join you?
-We're occupied right now. Beat it.
Ah, it's getting late. Go to bed, okay?
- Okay.
-Yeah. I'll run you upstairs.
- Good night, Grandma and Grandpa. Thank you.
Nighty-night. Sleep tight.
Ah, well, you've certainly had an adventure.
Well, yes. "Adventure" is one way to put it.
- How's Audrey?
-Oh, she's great.
Yeah, she and Stone, they seem
to be very happy.
Key word there is "seem."
- What do you mean?
-Their marriage is a sham.
- What?
-Well, they sleep around on each other.
- Been doing it for years.
-Oh, my gosh.
I just wish Audrey had found a more
solid marriage like you and Rusty.
Hey, Russ, can we talk?
I knew we had some problems.
Is it this bad?
Is our marriage dying?
No.
No, a marriage only dies
when you stop trying.
And you have never stopped trying.
I just think...
...maybe I did.
What do you mean?
I've only been thinking about
myself, you know?
I wanted to change the routine,
and go on exotic trips and...
Yeah, there's nothing wrong with that.
I was crazy to think I could make us
closer by locking us in a car for a week.
No, but you were doing that for us.
You have been trying so hard to make
this trip memorable for me and the kids...
...and I didn't appreciate that.
-But why would you?
I mean, I've put you through
some serious shit.
Literally, a pool of shit in Arkansas.
You deserve better.
What, better than you?
How many men would sacrifice their
careers for their family like you have?
Oh, I didn't sacrifice anything.
I have everything I've ever wanted.
- Debbie.
-Yeah'?
Will you continue to be my wife?
I wondered when you'd
give that back to me.
I was wondering if you still wanted it.
I do.
Wait a minute.
Are we gonna do this?
Oh, yeah. I'm gonna
pound the shit out of you.
- Russ.
-What?
Lock the door.
I'm gonna lock the shit out of that door.
- Hey, Dad.
-Morning, Rusty.
Could you drive us to the airport this afternoon?
There's a flight back to Chicago at 4.
Chicago?
What about Walls? World?
Oh, no. We've, uh, had enough.
- This trip's been a nightmare.
-Well, that's what family vacations are.
- But you can't give up, Russ.
-Well, why not?
I mean, they always say "its not
the destination, it's the journey," right'?
The journey sucks.
That's what makes you appreciate
the destination.
You had a dream to take your family
to Walley World.
Never let that go.
I know I didn't.
How would we even get to
Walla}; World? We don't have a car.
Hey, come on.
You leave that to me.
Oops, wrong door.
Could I, uh, take the Nissan?
Ha, ha. No, no.
Wait, Dad, I thought we were going
to the airport.
Boys, when your father makes you
a promise, he keeps it.
- That's not right.
-This sucks.
- Wow, this place is huge.
-Ha, ha.
This is dope as fuck.
Kevin.
Told you you guys would love it, right?
Hey, Dad.
- It really is dope as fuck.
- I know, right?
- Guys!
-Oh, wait!
There she is.
The Velociraptor.
- I can't believe we actually made it.
-Heh, I know.
- You guys ready for the ride of your life?
-Oh, yeah.
- If I'm being honest, it looks a little daunting.
-Ah!
- Come on. Race you to the ride.
-Yeah, go, go! Faster!
Come on!
Two more hours, guys.
Oh, my gosh.
- All right, guys. Get psyched.
-Yes.
This is it. This is why we came all this way.
Excuse us.
- What was that?
-Last ride tonight. Park's closing.
- No, we were next.
-What?
- That's not okay.
- Should be a misunderstanding.
Hey, excuse me.
You just cut in front of us.
No, see, we bought the Platinum Pass
so we get to skip the lines.
Fifth time today on this one.
Right, well, we just drove 2500 miles
to ride this ride...
...so you can't just take our spot.
Wait a minute, you...
Emma NY.
Yeah?
Good to see you. All right, I'll tell you what.
Why don't you and your family
go fuck yourselves?
I'm sorry, GUYS-
Oh, my God!
0K8)'-
You're a dead man.
- Get off!
-Oh, it's on.
Kevin, no!
No, you're not gonna fight.
- I'm not gonna stand here like a little bitch.
-What?
Oh, shit.
No, Kevin. Kevin, no. Kevin, come on.
You people are fucking crazy.
- What kind of a family are you?
-We're the Griswolds.
See you around...
...you piece of ass.
- Let's do this.
-All right.
- I haven't been in a fight like that for years.
-First car, all right.
Man, our family fucked that family up.
- We did.
-Did you see how I scratched that girl's arm?
Oh, I saw it, honey.
You gave her a good scratch.
My fingers still hurt a little, but I'll be okay.
Oh, boy. Here we go.
- Hold on.
-Oh, gosh!
There used to be a graying tower
Alone on the sea.
You became
The tight on the dark side 01' me
Love remained
A drug that's the high and not the pill
But did you knew
Thai when it snows
My eyes become large
And the light that you shine can be seen?
- Russ?
- Yeah?
Is it supposed to stay upside-down
like this?
Yeah, I don't think so.
Oh.
Dad, are we stuck?
Looks that way, pal.
My eyes, they're starting to bulge.
I'm sure they'll have us down any minute.
Well, guys, what'd you think
of Walley World?
Yeah.
Listen, boys, I can't tell you how much ifs
meant to me to spend all this time with you.
I love you more than anyihing in the world.
And if I could, I'd spend
every single day with you.
So we'll see you in a week.
- Wait, what's going on?
-Petersons will pick you up at O'Hare...
...and you'll stay with them.
-Where are we going?
Someplace I should've taken you
a longtime ago.
How did you get free tickets to Paris?
I used my connections as a pilot.
Oh, you're amazing, heh.
Well, you are my queen, and you
deserve lo be treated like one.
I know it's not exactly first-class...
...or coach...
-Honey...
...it's perfect.
-Yeah?
So...
...how long is the flight?
Twelve hours.
Perfect.